<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Communication rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/</link><description>Recent content in Communication rules on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Anonymous form link</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/anonymous-form-link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/anonymous-form-link/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule creates a link to a form which can be sent to an external user. The user can open the form without the need for authentication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/anonymousformlink.png" alt="Anonymous form link dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h6 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>To send an anonymous form link to an external user:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Before adding the rule, add a text field to store the anonymous link: Click on Controls &amp;gt; Input &amp;gt; Text and drag the field onto the form. Edit the field by clicking on it and then clicking the pen icon. Change the Title to &lt;em>Anonymous Link&lt;/em>. Change the Name(unique) to &lt;em>anonymousLink&lt;/em>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the Submit button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on Add a rule &amp;gt; Communications &amp;gt; Anonymous form link.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Action, Select a form to be completed by an external user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the Anonymous Link field where the link will be stored.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter a message for the external user. This message will be displayed when they submit the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Add a rule &amp;gt; Communications &amp;gt; Send email:
a. Add the external user&amp;rsquo;s email address under To:
b. Add a Subject.
c. Use the Expression builder to add [anonymousLink] to the Body of the email.
d. Refer to the documentation for the Send email rule, if required.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The field used to store the Anonymous Link can be made invisible to the user of the current form. Go to the field properties and set the field to &lt;em>not visible&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Each record or instance of a process can have only one active link.&lt;/em> If a second anonymous link is created for an instance of a process, the first link will not exist anymore. Users clicking on the first link will get an error message.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Link expire settings&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Options&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Never expires&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">The link will never expire.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Expire after a number of uses&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Add the number of uses before the link expires.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Expire in time&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Give the number of days, hours, and minutes before the link expires.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Hide form topbar: when selected, the tabs with the form names will not appear at top of the form opened by the external user.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Force log out: when set to Yes, the user will be logged out automatically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Meeting request rule</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/meeting-request/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/meeting-request/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule sends an email which includes a meeting request. It is the same as the Send email rule with three additional fields to add the details of the meeting:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Start time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>End time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Location&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you are using an email connector, a meeting request will appear in the calendar of the receiver(s). Otherwise the meeting request will appear as a calendar file (.ics file type) attached to an email.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To send a meeting request when the user submits a form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Before adding the rule, add fields to store the start date &amp;amp; time, the end date &amp;amp; time, and the location of the meeting:
a. Add a date field to the current form: Click on Controls &amp;gt; Input &amp;gt; Date and drag the field onto the form. Edit the field by clicking on it and then clicking the pen icon. Change the Title to &lt;em>Start&lt;/em>. Change the Name(unique) to &lt;em>start&lt;/em>. Set Display format to Date and time. Click OK.
b. Repeat the last step to add another field called &lt;em>End&lt;/em>.
c. Add a text field: Click on Controls &amp;gt; Input &amp;gt; Text and drag the field onto the form. Edit the field by clicking on it and then clicking the pen icon. Change the Title to &lt;em>Location&lt;/em>. Change the Name(unique) to &lt;em>location&lt;/em>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select the Submit button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a rule &amp;gt; Communications &amp;gt; Meeting request.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the Start time, select the Start field added earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For the End time, select the End field added earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And for the Location, select the Location field added earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continue as for the Send email rule.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Send email</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/send-email/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/send-email/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule sends an email according to a predefined template. Each element of the email is configurable. The body of the email can include text, images and attachments. Data stored in fields in the current form can be copied in dynamically.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use-the-send-email-rule">When to use the Send email rule&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="before-you-get-started">Before you get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In advance of using this rule, you need to have &lt;strong>created one or more forms, complete with control fields&lt;/strong>. For example a text box control with an employee&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo; may be part of a form &amp;lsquo;Annual Leave Request&amp;rsquo;. Then this &amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo; field can be used as an &lt;strong>expression&lt;/strong> in the email to send personalised emails, so these aspects must be set up in advance.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Decide how the rule will be implemented, for example will an email be sent once a form is saved or submitted. In the example of form submit, then click on that form in the process &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong> button &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Send email&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Decide who the automated email will be sent from, for example a no-reply type email. If you leave the From field empty, the email will be sent from &lt;a href="mailto:noreply@kianda.com">noreply@kianda.com&lt;/a>. If you want your email to come from a different sender, then go to [Email connector](#Email connector) for more details on how to set that up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any email addresses to send To, From, CC or BCC must be set up in advance. This could be a textbox in a form called &amp;lsquo;Email address&amp;rsquo; with a unique Name like &amp;rsquo;emailAddress&amp;rsquo;, or it could be a user picker field associated with particular users, groups or partners.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you want to track the emails, then you must set up a field in your form to store email tracking.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you want to attach any files to an email, files must first be stored in a File field in one of the forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on an existing process by going to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and decide which form, or field you will apply the rule to, by clicking on that item so that it is in &lt;strong>edit mode&lt;/strong> so you can see the Pen button, &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen button">. For example if the form Training Approval has a Submit button within a form and you want to attach the rule to Send an email when the form is submitted, then you need to click on the form and the Submit button in that form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/formvsbutton.png" alt="Form and button edit mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Communications&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Send email&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - of the email for example &amp;lsquo;Send email to Training Managers&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> - click on the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editconditions.png" alt="Edit conditions button"> create conditions to send the email, for example while a process has a &amp;lsquo;status&amp;rsquo; of &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo;. This type of status value can be set in a utility panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>From&lt;/strong> - who the email is from, click on &lt;strong>Person&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/person.png" alt="Person button"> and choose from the appropriate Selection mode, see [Selection mode](#Selection mode) below.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you add an email address to the From field then you must specify an Email connector, see [Email connector](#Email connector).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>To&lt;/strong> - who the email is to, click on &lt;strong>Person&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/person.png" alt="Person button"> and choose from the appropriate Selection mode, see [Selection mode](#Selection mode) below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CC&lt;/strong> - who will be copied on the email, as with &lt;strong>To&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>BCC&lt;/strong> - who will be blind copied on the email, as with &lt;strong>To&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Subject&lt;/strong> - type in your email subject and click on the &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis.png" alt="Ellipsis button"> to add an expression, go to [Expression builder](#Expression builder) for more information. The &lt;strong>Subject&lt;/strong> cannot be left empty.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Body&lt;/strong> - choose from an array of styles and formats to create your email including &lt;strong>Style,&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Colour&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font size&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Remove font style&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Font family&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Unordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Ordered list&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Paragraph&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Table&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Picture&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Attach a File&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Code view&lt;/strong>. For example if you click on &lt;strong>Code view&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/%5Ccode.png" alt="Code view button"> you can copy HTML code directly into the body text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/email.png" alt="Send email">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To find out more about how to attach a file, see &lt;a href="#Attachments">Attachments&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click into body text to type in your text. If you want a useful way to personalise automated emails using fields from the forms you have created click on the &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis.png" alt="Ellipsis button"> to add an expression, see [Expression builder](#Expression builder) for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Send via connector&lt;/strong> - options are a) No or b) Yes&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then you must choose an &lt;strong>Email connector&lt;/strong> and decide if you want to &lt;strong>Save Sent Items&lt;/strong> (Yes or No) which means sent emails are saved in a sent items folder in your email account. For more information go to [Email connector](#Email connector)
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/emailconnector.png" alt="Email connector options">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable tracking&lt;/strong> - options are a) No or b) Yes&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note that this option is only available if &lt;strong>Send via connector&lt;/strong> is set to &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> and the email is being sent from &lt;a href="mailto:noreply@kianda.com">noreply@kianda.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then you must click into the field under &lt;strong>Field to store tracking event (Open, Click, Bounce, Spam)&lt;/strong> and choose a field from a form to store the event.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/enabletrackingyes.png" alt="Enable tracking">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This option allows you to track the email after it is sent. All of these events, Open, Click, Bounce and Spam will be tracked.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Note when your rule is complete you may want to change the order of rules for the particular field or form that it has been applied to. Drag the new Send email rule to where you want, so the order of execution of rules is correct.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example for a Submit button on a form I may want my &lt;strong>Send email rule&lt;/strong> to be executed first before any other rule is executed. To do this click on the &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong> button to make sure you are in &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> mode, and under &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> in the right-hand pane, drag the &lt;strong>Send email&lt;/strong> rule to the top of the list by clicking on the rule and dragging it to the top.
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ruleorder.png" alt="Rule order">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information on rules, see &lt;a href="rules/Readme.md">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="email-connector">Email connector&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The email connector must be set up in advance TO COME BACK TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you leave the From field empty, the email will be sent from &lt;a href="mailto:noreply@kianda.com">noreply@kianda.com&lt;/a>. If you want your email to come from a different sender, follow these steps when you are editing the Send email rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Set &lt;strong>Send via connector&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click into the field under &lt;strong>Email connector&lt;/strong> and select a connector.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Note that this will override the global Email connector setting if one has been configured for your system. Go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Subscription&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Subscription Details&lt;/strong> to check for a global setting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="selection-mode">Selection mode&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you are filling out the &lt;strong>To&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>From&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>CC&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>BCC&lt;/strong> fields and click on the &lt;strong>Person&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/person.png" alt="Person button">you have the following selection mode options to choose from: &lt;strong>Any user or partner&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>User(s) defined in a user field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Form owner(s)&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Email address in a field&lt;/strong>. Each option is explained below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/anygroups2.png" alt="Any user or partner mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please note in all modes you can clear a field by clicking on the field and click on &lt;strong>Clear field&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clearx.png" alt="Clear field">.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Any user or partner&lt;/strong> - if you choose this option, then click on &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> and choose from Users, Groups or Partners and click into the field under &lt;strong>Select users&lt;/strong> to see a dropdown list of users, predefined groups and partners and click onto your name of choice. You can add as many users, groups and partners as desired by clicking on a name in the list, or remove by clicking on the name within the field for example HR Team.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clearfield.png" alt="Clear user field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ Clear the field if needed clicking on the field and click on &lt;strong>Clear&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clearx.png" alt="Clear field">.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User(s) defined in a user field&lt;/strong> - if you choose this option, it means the user name is already defined in a form. Click on &lt;strong>User picker&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpicker.png" alt="User picker button"> and click into the field under &lt;strong>Select a user field&lt;/strong> to see a user picker field or other field within a form, where the user (email address), for example &amp;lsquo;Line Manager&amp;rsquo; is within the form Employee Request&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpickerfield.png" alt="Select a user field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the field to add to the list. You can add as many fields as desired by clicking on the &lt;strong>User picker&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpicker.png" alt="User picker button"> or remove a field by clicking on the field or by clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/nameduserpicker.png" alt="User defined field">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Form owner(s)&lt;/strong> - if you choose this option, then click click into the field under &lt;strong>Form owner of selected form&lt;/strong> and choose from the forms within that process, where the form owner(s) email addresses will be selected.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/formowners.png" alt="Form owner of selected form">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>Email address in a field - if you choose this option, then click into the field under &lt;strong>Type the address or select from a field&lt;/strong> and either type in an email address or choose from a field within a form within that process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectemailusers.png" alt="select email users">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In all cases when you have made your selection, click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="expression-builder">Expression builder&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The expression builder is a useful and efficient way to use existing form fields as part of automated emails that you want to send out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example if you have a form Annual Leave request that contains a text box field &amp;lsquo;Employee Name&amp;rsquo; you can use this field in an automated email to let a manager know that an employee has submitted an a request.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Before you begin have your body text inserted into the &lt;strong>Body&lt;/strong> of the email and position your cursor where you want to add an expression, for example an Employee Name after &amp;lsquo;Your employee&amp;rsquo; as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bodytext.png" alt="Body text">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis.png" alt="Ellipsis button">beside email &lt;strong>Body&lt;/strong> then the Expression builder dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click into the field under &lt;strong>Add field to expression&lt;/strong>. Forms and fields that are part of your process appear where you can expand elements to drill down to find the field that you want, for example &amp;lsquo;Employee Name&amp;rsquo;. Click on the field to add field to the expression.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expressionaddfield.png" alt="Expression builder">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Add to expression&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addtoexpression.png" alt="Add to expression">to add the field as an expression.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expressionadded.png" alt="Expression added">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The result is the expression is now part of the automated email.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expressionin.png" alt="Text box expression added">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add more expressions, firstly position your cursor in your body text where you want to add the expression, then click on the &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button and under &lt;strong>Add field to expression&lt;/strong> clear any existing fields by clicking on the &lt;strong>Clear&lt;/strong> button. This appears when you hover over the Add field box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clearexpression.png" alt="Clear field">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then search for other fields, for example lists or links, and use the Expression reference functions, see step 7.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on Reference button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/reference.png" alt="Expression reference"> button to find out how to use particular functions in your email. For example &lt;strong>ProcessLink()&lt;/strong> returns the html link to the current process. Copy this function into the Expression box and click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to add the function. Then in the &lt;strong>Body&lt;/strong> type in the text you want associated with this link for example &amp;ldquo;click here&amp;rdquo; into the brackets of the function:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clickhere.png" alt="Click here text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this way you can build sophisticated automated emails that provide a link back to a process instance, for example that a manager can view, update or approve. For more information on References and Expressions see &lt;a href="expressions.md">Expressions&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="attachments">Attachments&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To attach a file to an automated email, click on the &lt;strong>Attach a file&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/attachfile.png" alt="Attach a file button"> and the Attach file to email dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Attachments&lt;/strong>: Files can be attached to the email. First the file must be stored in a File field in one of the forms. Open the Send Email rule and find the File icon in the Body field menu. Click in the File field to find the field where the file is stored. Click on Insert attachment. There is an option to attach a link to the file rather than the file itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: User alert</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/user-alert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/user-alert/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule sends an alert to a user who can then open an instance of a process. A user can view all alerts by clicking on the bell icon on the top right-hand corner of their screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/useralert.png" alt="User alert dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To send an alert to the current user:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select the Submit button&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a rule &amp;gt;Communications &amp;gt; User Alert&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Current user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter a title for the Alert.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter a message to be displayed to the user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select a colour to indicate the Alert Status.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose an Alert icon e.g. flag.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Send alert to:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Option&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Notes&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Any user&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Select from any user in the system.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Current user&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">The current user will get an alert.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Defined in a user field&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Select a user picker field which stores the user to receive the alert.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Form owner(s)&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Select the form and the owner(s) will receive the alert.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Process ID:&lt;/strong>
When the user receives an alert and clicks on it, he will open the process instance defined in the Process ID field.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If left blank, this field will contain the current Process ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A different process ID can be added by typing or copying in the ID (or if the Process ID is stored in a field, then that field can be selected).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>