<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Publish your process</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/</link><description>Recent content in Publish your process on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Dashboards</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/dashboards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/dashboards/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>dashboards&lt;/strong> deliver a convenient way to provide insights into how your business processes are performing. Kianda dashboards offer easy reporting, permissions management, quick build, condition-based filtering and many more features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From lists to tiles, filter and charts, dashboards allow you to build full digital experiences to monitor your real-time processes in a few minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 3 steps involved in creating a dashboard:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Create a dashboard page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add one or more widgets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configure or edit the widgets to make the page look the way you want.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If you are using Kianda predefined processes from the App Store or other imported processes, then dashboards have already been created for you! These are available by clicking on &lt;strong>Dashboard&lt;/strong> from the side menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you begin it is important to be aware that there are two modes involved in dashboard pages, an &lt;a href="#edit-mode-and-view-mode">Edit mode and View mode&lt;/a> as described below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="edit-mode-and-view-mode">Edit mode and View mode&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When using dashboards there are two modes: &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>View mode&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you are in &lt;strong>View mode&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit2.PNG" alt="Edit button"> will be visible in the top menu bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Clicking on the Edit button to go into Edit mode&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashboardgeneral.png" alt="View mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit2.PNG" alt="Edit button"> you will be in &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong>, which means that the &lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong> is available at the top of the dashboard page, along with the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings2.png" alt="Settings"> to make changes to the page, and &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin button"> to delete the page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editmode.png" alt="Edit mode">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;strong>Edit mode,&lt;/strong> you can also make changes to widgets s &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/pen.png" alt="Pen button">, &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog.png" alt="Cog button">and &lt;strong>Delete&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin button"> buttons, will be available. If you want to create a dashboard page from scratch go to &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a> or if you want to learn more about dashboard widgets go to &lt;a href="#dashboard-widgets">Dashboard widgets&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kianda offers a user-friendly interface to create dashboards in a few minutes. Please follow the below video to learn how to create dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Dashboards introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/dashboards.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a dashboard, go to &lt;strong>Home&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/home2.PNG" alt="Home button">in the left-hand pane and click on &lt;strong>Create a new page&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/newpages.PNG" alt="Create a new page">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Create dashboard page dialog box&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/createdashboard.png" alt="Create dashboard page">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - dashboard title for example Training Requests&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the dashboard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - determine who will see the dashboard, choose from a) Users b) Groups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Icon&lt;/strong> - click on the arrow to choose from hundreds of icons to attach to your dashboard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sort order&lt;/strong> - choose a numeric value to sort on by click&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong> - define a group who will use this dashboard, for example HR managers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enable favourites&lt;/strong> checkbox - tick this checkbox if you want to enable this dashboard as a &amp;lsquo;favourite&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing the field to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The output is a menu with a number of widgets available that you can add to the dashboard. Go to &lt;a href="#dashboard-widgets">Dashboard widgets&lt;/a> to find out more about each widget type.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Widget menu&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/trainingdashboard.png" alt="Widget menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you wish to change settings for the dashboard page, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings2.png" alt="Settings"> see &lt;a href="#dashboard-page-settings">Dashboard page settings&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you want to delete the dashboard page, click on the &lt;strong>Bin&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> to confirm that you want to delete the dashboard page or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/savepage.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you will see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You are now in &lt;strong>View mode&lt;/strong>. To make further changes to the dashboard page, return to &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit2.PNG" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="dashboard-widgets">Dashboard widgets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kianda comes with 7 predefined widgets as listed below. Using these widgets you can quickly and easily create a process dashboard in minutes. The widgets are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Rich text&lt;/strong>: The Rich text is used to display some texts, links or images on the dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tile&lt;/strong>: A tile is used to display a count of instances with different colour schemes. You could also add conditions to display count, for example, you could add a condition “Status” equals “In-progress”, this will display the count of instances with status “In-progress”.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chart:&lt;/strong> Using a chart widget, you could create a pie chart, bar chart or a line chart. These charts could be used to represent various conditions on a process,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>List:&lt;/strong> The list widget displays the instances of the selected process. List widget could also be used to connect with any other widget to display the filtered items,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Filter:&lt;/strong> The filter widget is used to filter the instances based on a field. For example, process instances could be filtered by status.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Link:&lt;/strong> The link widget is used to add a link to a new process, dashboard or any external sources such as SharePoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Walk-through:&lt;/strong> This widget allows you to create a walk-through quickly which could be made available to a user, group or an organisation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you have added one or more widgets, you can move the widgets around the dashboard page using the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite.png" alt="Drag handle button">. This is possible when you are in &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong>, see &lt;a href="#edit-mode-and-view-mode">Edit mode and View mode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dashboard-page-settings">Dashboard page settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When you click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings2.png" alt="Settings"> a &lt;strong>Page settings&lt;/strong> dialog box opens. The edit options are the same as &lt;strong>Create dashboard page&lt;/strong> dialog box that appears during page creation, see &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a> but also includes &lt;strong>two&lt;/strong> additional checkboxes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display in mobile footer&lt;/strong> - tick this checkbox if you want to display dashboard in the mobile footer&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide from navigation&lt;/strong> - tick this checkbox if you want to hide the dashboard from navigation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Page settings&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dashsettings.png" alt="Dashboard settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing the field to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="enabling-data-export-from-dashboards">Enabling data export from dashboards&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kianda allows the users to export the data from the dashboards on a simple click. To set up the configuration to export the data from the dashboards, please follow the below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Enabling data export from dashboards&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/Enabling data export from the dashboards.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>
&lt;h3 id="offline-availability">Offline availability&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kianda is a progressive web application. This enables Kianda dashboards to provide insights to the business processes even in offline mode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, this can benefit businesses where users can carry out inspections or maintenance even at a remote location with no access to the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you would like to see examples of &amp;lsquo;how to&amp;rsquo; perform particular tasks in Kianda, click on the link below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/how-to/">Short &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; videos&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="to-return-to-the-previous-pages-click-on-the-links-below--lighting-iconimages10png">&lt;strong>To return to the previous pages click on the links below&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/10.png" alt="Lighting icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/how-kianda-works/">&lt;strong>How Kianda works&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/preview-your-process/">&lt;strong>Preview the design&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/">&lt;strong>Publish your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>