<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/</link><description>Recent content in Rules on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: General</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="business-process-rules">Business Process Rules&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Business rules are what makes Kianda forms come alive. They represent the actual actions users intend to perform when they interact with form components.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="categories">Categories&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Workflow&lt;/strong> - Enables you to execute actions that might change the flow of the information within a process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Communications&lt;/strong> - Enables sending emails or meeting requests or even user (push) notifications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong> - This is an important and flexible rule group because it allows you to configure CRUD (Create, Read, Update and Delete) actions to configured data sources.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> - This enables you to retrieve a user property, updating user properties or lookup for a user based on a user attribute.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>File management&lt;/strong> - Allows operations such as the generation of a word document and conversion to PDF and more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tables&lt;/strong> - Provides specialised rules to enable working with tables like sorting, copying table rows to another table and more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dates&lt;/strong> - Enables convenient date calculation with advanced options like ignoring weekends or special dates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Form actions&lt;/strong> - Allows operations like submit, save, close and delete forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong> - Provides a variety of operations to be performed on the SharePoint connection. These rules include operations like create a list, find a user, define permission to an item, check-in / out an item or adding a user to a SharePoint group.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="working-with-rules">Working with rules&lt;/h4>
&lt;h5 id="where-to-add-a-rule">Where to Add a rule&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="how-to-add-a-rule">How to Add a rule&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>To add a rule to a specific component:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select the field you want.
Under Add a rule, select the rule you want.
Edit the rule and click &amp;lsquo;OK&amp;rsquo; - the rule will be displayed on the right-hand side of the page&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="how-to-copy-a-rule">How to Copy a rule&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Duplicating rules can be very useful in case you have similar rules that are in different fields. To duplicate a rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select the field with the desired rule
Click on the Clone rule button, next to the rule name
Optionally, modify the rule settings&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="how-to-view-a-rule">How to View a rule&lt;/h5>
&lt;h5 id="how-to-edit-a-rule">How to Edit a rule&lt;/h5>
&lt;h5 id="how-to-disable-a-rule">How to Disable a rule&lt;/h5>
&lt;h5 id="where-to-place-a-rule-in-a-list-of-rules">Where to place a rule in a list of rules&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Select the field with the rules.
On the Rules section, drag and drop the rules in the order you want them.
Submit, save, close
If there is a Condition, then the fields must be set before it is run
Example: Set Status, Send Email, Submit, Save, Close&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="conditions">Conditions&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Flexible and dynamic conditions form an important component to make forms fully dynamic. It enables you to create natural language conditions when rules should be triggered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/condition-editor.png" alt="Condition Editor">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To configure a rule to conditionally execute an action:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on Edit conditions button within the rule.
Add the conditions that satisfy your scenario.
Multiple conditions can be grouped with condition groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="custom-rules">Custom rules&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Under custom rules, you will find any custom-developed rules available under your developer section. Custom rules provide access to rules that are built for extensibility of Kianda capabilities. This is particularly used in situations when existing rules do not provide the required functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Custom rules have the purpose of providing a user interface for the end-users. If you need to build &amp;ldquo;a rule&amp;rdquo; then you should use a custom rule widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It allows a developer to quickly build a reusable component that would then be used by process designers in real processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check-out the &lt;a href="development.md">development&lt;/a> section for more details on how to build custom widgets in Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../workflow/">Workflow&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_communications.md">Communications&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_data.md">Data&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_users.md">Users&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_file_management.md">File management&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_tables.md">Tables&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_dates.md">Dates&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_form_actions.md">Form actions&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_sharepoint.md">Sharepoint&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="rules_kianda_ai.md">Kianda_AI&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Workflow rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Communication rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/communications/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Communication rules is one category of &lt;a href="rules/Readme.md">rules&lt;/a> to enable automated communications with process users, for example sending meeting requests or even user push notifications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-communication-rules">Getting started with Communication rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the Communication rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Communications&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/communications.png" alt="Communication rules">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are four types of Communication rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Send email&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Meeting request&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Anonymous form link&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>User alert&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about each of the rule types go to the links below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Data rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/data/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Data rules is the category of rules that enables that flow between data connectors and form elements, for example reading or writing data from a database table or performing data manipulation with the &lt;a href="set_form_field.md">Set form field rule&lt;/a> expressions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-data-rules">Getting started with Data rules&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you go to &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process or create a new process, then click on &lt;strong>Add a rule&lt;/strong> the Data rules are found in the left-hand pane when you click on &lt;strong>Data&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are five types of data rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Create item - Use this rule together with a datasource to perform a create / insert query and return data identifiers for use with the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Delete item - Use this rule together with a datasource to perform a delete query and return data identifiers for use with the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Update item - Use this rule together with a datasource to perform an update query and return data identifiers for use with the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Find Items - Use this rule together with a datasource to perform a query and return data for use with the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Set form field - This rule is used to update the value of fields in a form. Use this rule to copy content between fields or to apply a custom expression to set the value of a given field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the five types of &lt;strong>Data rules&lt;/strong>. Click on the links below to find out more about each rule in detail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: User rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/users/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: File management rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/files/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Table rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/tables/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Date rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/dates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/dates/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Form action rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/form-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/form-actions/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Rules within the form action rules allow to perform form specific actions such as saving a form / process, submiting a form, closing a form, deleting a process and validating form input.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 6 form action rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: AI rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/kianda-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/kianda-ai/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Artificial Intelligence powered text analysis performs sentiment analysis to text content&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: SharePoint rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/sharepoint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/sharepoint/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="getting-started-with-sharepoint-rules">Getting started with SharePoint rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>SharePoint rules are associated with SharePoint specific functionality. These rules are typically used to perform actions with SharePoint connectors that are not related with data, for example resetting SharePoint permissions or adding a user into a group on SharePoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 10 SharePoint rules as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create a list&lt;/strong> - creates a new list in a SharePoint site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create a site&lt;/strong> - creates a new site on SharePoint, enabling the use of a site template.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create a group&lt;/strong> - creates a new group on SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Find a user&lt;/strong> - finds or searches for a user within SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Add a user to a group&lt;/strong> - adds a SharePoint user to a SharePoint group. It is important to note the difference between Sharepoint users and Kianda users. Sharepoint users are users of the Sharepoint system. Kianda users are users of the Kianda system.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Remove a user from a group&lt;/strong> - removes a SharePoint user from a SharePoint group&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reset an item permission&lt;/strong>s - changes the SharePoint permissions for a given list, document or folder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Check in / out an item&lt;/strong> - checks in or out a file in SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Get attachments&lt;/strong> - reads the attachments from a SharePoint list&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create anonymous link&lt;/strong> - creates anonymous links for a SharePoint held file&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have briefly introduced each of the ten types of &lt;strong>SharePoint rules&lt;/strong>. Click on the links below to find out more about each rule in detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>