<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Add forms</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/</link><description>Recent content in Add forms on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Version history</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/version-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/version-history/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>current or active version&lt;/strong> of a process is always visible in the right-hand pane, for example V0.8 for the process as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Process version&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/versionhistory.png" alt="Process version history">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>first version&lt;/strong> of a process is &lt;strong>0.1&lt;/strong> and will increment to 0.2 and so on, each time a process is saved. Once the process is &lt;strong>published&lt;/strong> the version changes to &lt;strong>1.0&lt;/strong> and increments with each publication. This makes it is easy to keep track of who made changes and when, and to restore an older version if needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The video below introduces version control and the section &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a> runs through how to view process versions and restore an older version.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Version control&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/versioncontrol.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To view the version history click on the &lt;strong>Design version history&lt;/strong> button which may look like V0.1 or whatever the current version is for your process, for example &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version1.png" alt="View design version history"> or &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version 0.8">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A pop-up shows the version history details including when the version was created and who created it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example below, there are 8 versions of the process, all are &lt;strong>drafts&lt;/strong> indicated by the 0 in front, such as 0.8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Version history&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/versions.png" alt="Version history details">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on a particular version to see the version information, for example forms, fields and rules that were added, modified or removed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Version details&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/versiondetails.png" alt="Version details">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To restore an earlier version, click on the &lt;strong>Restore&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/restore.png" alt="Restore button"> beside a particular version and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> to confirm that you want to restore to that version.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To learn more about adding different elements to your form go to &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/">Add controls and rules&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="to-return-to-the-previous-pages-click-on-the-links-below--idea-iconimages10png">&lt;strong>To return to the previous pages click on the links below&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/10.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/">&lt;strong>Design and build your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/">&lt;strong>Add forms&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/designer/">&lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/">&lt;strong>Add controls and rules&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/preview-your-process/">&lt;strong>Preview the design&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Designer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/designer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/designer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> provides an intuitive interface where you can quickly start building &lt;strong>forms&lt;/strong> for any business use case. Forms are an important component of any process. They might be used as a stage of a process and can be made active individually or at the same time (parallel forms).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 3 key principles to consider when working with forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Form &lt;strong>design&lt;/strong> - what a form looks like, what elements it contains, for example controls and rules, see &lt;a href="#designer-layout">&lt;strong>Designer layout&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form &lt;strong>interaction&lt;/strong>- how users can use forms depending on certain sequences happening, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/rules/">&lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Form &lt;strong>management&lt;/strong> - who can edit and access forms is set when creating a new form, see &lt;a href="#new-forms">&lt;strong>New forms&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="designer-layout">Designer layout&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To access processes, go to the left-hand pane and &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> and click on a process that you have created or imported, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/">Design and build your process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the main process view, click on any process to add forms, for example Training process as seen below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Main process view&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>
&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clickonprocess.png" alt="Clicking on a process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The designer window opens and is made up of 3 main parts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Kianda Designer&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/formdesigner_frame.png" alt="Form designer">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key components of the designer are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Left-hand pane is used to add form elements like &lt;strong>controls&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>rules&lt;/strong>. This pane also houses the &lt;strong>Exit&lt;/strong> Designer &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exitdesign.png" alt="Exit"> &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save"> &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview"> and &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/publish.png" alt="Publish"> buttons.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Central &lt;strong>form canvas&lt;/strong> displays the current form you are working on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Right-hand pane is used to view and edit process, form and field &lt;strong>properties&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Note the name of the process you are working on is shown in the top menu bar, for example Training Process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The video below demonstrates how to get started using Kianda Designer, and go to &lt;a href="#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a> to follow through on different ways to import forms or start from scratch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Introduction to Kianda Designer&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/designerintro.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How you get started with forms depends on:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>if you have created a process using the App Store, see &lt;a href="#predefined-forms">Predefined forms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>if you have created a process from scratch or want to create a form from scratch, see &lt;a href="#new-forms">New forms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>if you import forms that have already been created, see &lt;a href="#import-forms">Import forms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once your form is created, you are ready to start adding elements to your form, see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/">Add controls and rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In addition there are a number of settings you can change, see &lt;a href="#settings-and-properties">Settings and Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="predefined-forms">Predefined forms&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you have created a process using the &lt;strong>App Store,&lt;/strong> then a number of forms will already be part of the process. For example the process Security Incident Management has 5 forms attached: Incident detail, Data breach, Malware outbreak, Root cause remedy and Caller review.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To edit form details, simply click on a form and click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> to edit the form. You can also click on the &lt;strong>Add form&lt;/strong> button to add a new form. Edit options are shown under &lt;a href="#new-forms">New forms&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="new-forms">New forms&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you have created a process from scratch, an empty form is added to your process by default, called &amp;ldquo;form 1&amp;rdquo;. This is the first form. Click on this form and the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> to customise it. You can also click on the &lt;strong>Add form&lt;/strong> button to add a new form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Adding a form&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/createnewform.png" alt="Edit form">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>There are a number of edit options below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Editing a form&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editform.png" alt="Edit form options">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: as you change any of the options in the dialog box, the impact will be shown in real-time on the form in the background, for example a title, or colour form theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the form title, for example Employee Request Form&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the form&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Default owner(s)&lt;/strong> - by default the form creator is an owner. You can remove this owner by clicking on &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/x.png" alt="x"> and add other owners by clicking on the arrow and choose from &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Partners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Users - allows you to choose individual owners&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Groups - allows you to choose from defined groups for example HR Team or Management Team&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partners - allows you to choose predefined partner organisations that you want to share with or provide permissions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Activate with&lt;/strong> - will decide when the form will be active. If you have several forms attached to a process, then select from a dropdown list the form you want to activate with the current form. If you leave the field blank, the new form will be activated &lt;strong>sequentially&lt;/strong> after the first form is submitted.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Submit mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) Only this form (the current form) or b) All forms in edit mode&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form icon&lt;/strong> - click on the arrow to choose from hundreds of icons to attach to your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Form theme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable quick actions&lt;/strong> - if you tick the checkbox, you can select from the options a) Enable re-assign b) Enable edit and c) Enable custom action. Click on &lt;strong>Ellipsis&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ellipsis_frame.png" alt="Ellipsis button"> to further modify the action settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on &lt;strong>Enable re-assign&lt;/strong>, you can reassign action settings to particular Users, Groups or Partners. Click on &lt;strong>Allow form owners&lt;/strong> if you want form owners to be able to reassign actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on &lt;strong>Enable edit&lt;/strong>, you can allow certain Users, Groups or Partners to edit the form, along with form owners by clicking on &lt;strong>Allow form owners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other options include a checkbox for &lt;strong>When editing auto hide form footer buttons&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Trigger rules on save&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you check &lt;strong>Trigger rules on save&lt;/strong> then click into the &lt;strong>Save action field&lt;/strong> to choose from an action trigger as to when the form is saved, for example Submit, Save or Close. These can be other actions depending on what you have defined.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Edit action settings&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editactions.png" alt="Edit action settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you click on &lt;strong>Enable custom action&lt;/strong>, you can allow certain Users, Groups or Partners to edit the form, along with form owners by clicking on &lt;strong>Allow form owners&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other options include &lt;strong>Action label&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Target action field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Action display mode&lt;/strong>, for example &lt;strong>Read-only mode&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Both&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Custom action settings&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/customactionsettings.png" alt="Custom action settings">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>As a form designer you can set up actions dependent on certain conditions, for example an Action label that targets a certain button appearing for example Close button, only when a certain display mode is chosen, for example Read-only mode. If &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> is chosen, then the button will only appear when the form is being &lt;strong>edited&lt;/strong>. In this way you can create dynamic forms that suit user interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To save your changes to the form, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You are now ready to start adding &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/">Controls and rules&lt;/a> to your form. You can also implement additional settings see &lt;a href="#process-settings">Process Settings&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="import-forms">Import forms&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can import a previously designed form by clicking on the &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importform.png" alt="Import button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the arrow to select from the drop down list to &lt;strong>Select a process design&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on a &lt;strong>process&lt;/strong> of interest and then click on the forms to import. Forms are indicated by a + symbol and can be expanded to show elements within a form for example a panel containing different fields such as lists and text boxes. This means you can import a whole form, or just elements of a form. In this way you can very quickly reuse some or all parts of an existing form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Importing from another process&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/importfromprocess.png" alt="Import from another process">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="adding-form-elements">Adding form elements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you have added a new form during the form creation process, then a blank canvas with 3 default buttons are available to you: &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Default form buttons&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/defaultbuttons.png" alt="Form button edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/">Add controls and rules&lt;/a> to find out more about adding form elements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move elements by clicking on the &lt;strong>Drag Handle&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/move.png" alt="Drag handle"> beside the item and dragging it to where you want to place it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit elements by clicking on each item and clicking on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> see &lt;a href="#settings-and-properties">Settings and properties&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="settings-and-properties">Settings and Properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to the edits above, there are a number other actions and settings that you can implement to your process and forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Settings and properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settingsprocess.png" alt="Process and form properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Settings are available from the right-hand pane and give you the ability to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#import-forms">Import processes&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>View &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/version-history/">Version history&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Change &lt;a href="#process-settings">Process settings&lt;/a> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings button">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Edit form information by selecting a form and clicking on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Change a field to another field by clicking on &lt;strong>Change field&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Create a duplicate form by selecting a form, clicking on the &lt;strong>Clone&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/clone.png" alt="Clone button"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong>. A version called &amp;lsquo;Form Name Copy&amp;rsquo; is created and available to edit on the canvas. The &lt;strong>Clone&lt;/strong> button can also be used to clone form elements like controls or buttons.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Delete a form by selecting a form, clicking on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the form title and you are sure this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>View and edit &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/properties#form-properties">Form properties&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/rules/">rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="process-settings">Process settings&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can edit process settings by clicking on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/settings.png" alt="Settings button"> in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Process id settings&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Default or b) Custom and use a combination of [ProcessName]-[UniqueNumber]-[FieldName]&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable process security&lt;/strong> - if you tick the checkbox, can allow certain Users, Groups or Partners to have certain privileges related to the radio button options to create, assign and view as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Enable process security&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process_security.png" alt="Process security">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default setting is &lt;strong>Security users can create, assign to can update, everyone else can view&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On load rules execution mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) Always b) When in edit mode or c) When open new. The default setting is &lt;strong>Always&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide form tabs&lt;/strong> - gives you the ability to hide form tabs, options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hide left nav&lt;/strong> - gives you the ability to hide navigation elements, options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable anonymous sharing of forms&lt;/strong> - gives you the ability to share forms with people outside your organisation for example a feedback form or GDPR subject access request. Options are a) Yes or b) No. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> there are various options that you can add:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Message to display after anonymous submission&lt;/strong> - to add a display message&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Enabling anonymous sharing&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/anonlink.png" alt="Link for external users">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Hide form topbar&lt;/strong> - checkbox to hide the form topbar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Force log out&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No to force user logout once the form is submitted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>New link&lt;/strong> to generate a new anonymous form link to share with users and click on &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> to change the link.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable mobile bottom navigation&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instance delete settings&lt;/strong> - options are a) Any user can delete b) Creator can delete c) &amp;ldquo;Current form owner&amp;rdquo; can delete d) &amp;ldquo;Security users&amp;rdquo; can delete e) &amp;ldquo;Admins only&amp;rdquo; can delete. The default setting is &lt;strong>Creator can delete&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable form assignment notification&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prevent closing instance with unsaved data&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Selected tab theme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White as a colour when a form is selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Completed tab theme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White as a colour when a form is completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Exit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/exitdesign.png" alt="Exit process"> to go back to the process list, the Save button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> to save your work, the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview"> to preview what you have created and the &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/publish.png" alt="Publish button"> to publish your work.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To learn more about rules and controls that can be applied to forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/controls/">&lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/rules/">&lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To learn more about properties, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/properties#field-properties">&lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="user-tips-target-iconimages05png">User tips &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/05.png" alt="Target icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>There are many ways to then reuse elements within forms, see the video &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/how-to/reuse-or-clone-process-elements/">&lt;strong>Reusability&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There are many ways to manage who has access to a process, or form, see the video &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/how-to/control-form-user-security/">&lt;strong>User management&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="to-return-to-the-previous-pages-click-on-the-links-below--idea-iconimages10png">&lt;strong>To return to the previous pages click on the links below&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/10.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/how-kianda-works/">&lt;strong>How Kianda works&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/low-code/">&lt;strong>What is low-code development&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/no-code/">&lt;strong>What is no-code development&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/">&lt;strong>Design and build your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-forms/">&lt;strong>Add forms&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/">Add controls and rules&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/add-controls-and-rules/properties/">&lt;strong>Properties&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>