<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Dashboard pages</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Dashboard pages on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs:</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/listviewfields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/listviewfields/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="list-view-fields">List view fields&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When you choose the List widget for your dashboard, there are a number of ways to select fields that you want to view.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/pen.png" alt="Pen button">in the widget you have created, to see the &lt;strong>List view fields&lt;/strong> visible in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="images/listconfig_frame.png" alt="List view fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> to see a list of commonly used dashboard fields such as &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Created by&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Modified&amp;rsquo;. Click on as many fields as needed to add to the dashboard, for example 3 fields are selected below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="images/commonfields.png" alt="Common fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> again to close the options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong> to see a list of all the fields used in the design of the forms used in the chosen process. For example the Training Process shown below has 2 forms, &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Training Approval&amp;rsquo; and all control fields used in the form design are available to choose as filters for the dashboard. Click on the + symbol to drill down into the form, and click on the relevant fields to use them, for example Name, Type of Training and Management Decision have been chosen below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="images/designfields.png" alt="Design fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong> again to close the options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Clicking on &lt;strong>List fields&lt;/strong> shows you a list of all the fields you have already chosen from &lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Design fields&lt;/strong>. There is also an option to &lt;strong>Add column&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Add action&lt;/strong>. You can change the order of the fields as they appear in the list from left to right by clicking on the Drag handle button &lt;img src="images/draghandlewhite.png" alt="Drag handle">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="images/listfields.png" alt="List fields">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TO COME BACK TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change the list settings, that is the way the list looks, title and so on, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and go to &lt;a href="pages/list.md">List widget&lt;/a> to find out more about edit options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="images/penbutton.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="#list.md">List widget&lt;/a> to find out about other sorting and search options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Chart widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/chart/</guid><description>
&lt;p>With the chart widget, you can create pie, bar or line charts. These charts can be used to represent various conditions for a process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After creating a dashboard page, make sure you are in Edit mode, by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> at the top of the page, so the Widget menu with 7 widget types is available. Then click on the Chart widget &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/chart.png" alt="Chart widget">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addchartwidget.png" alt="Add chart widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the dashboard title, for example Type of Training&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - control the size of the dashboard, choose from 1 to 12 columns in width. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a panel that is 6 columns wide, or click on the right of the blue bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> checkbox - tick this checkbox if you wish to show a header on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - determine who will see the dashboard, choose from a) Users b) Groups&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - choose from icons for deshtop, tablet, mobile, wifi and flightmode as to when the device can view the dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing the dashboard to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can then edit the widget to display certain fields from your form, that relates to the data you are interested in. Go to &lt;a href="#configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you will see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton_frame.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To re-edit the title, colour scheme or other options in Step 2, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box options, allowing you to make changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the widget at any stage, click on the &lt;strong>Bin&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin button"> beside the cog button, and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> to confirm that you want to delete the dashboard page or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button in a chart widget you have created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/chartpen.png" alt="Chart widget edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A dialog box opens with filter options in the left-hand pane, a &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="C:%5CKianda%5Cdocs-dev%5Cpages%5Cchart.assets%5Cconditions.png" alt="Conditions">in the middle of the box, and chart edit fields in the right-hand pane. Go to &lt;a href="pages/conditions.md">Conditions&lt;/a> to read more about conditions you can apply to data and go to &lt;a href="pages/chartviewfields.md">Chart view fields&lt;/a> to read more about changing how a chart looks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editchart.png" alt="Editing a chart widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first option on the left is to choose is where the data should originate from using the &lt;strong>Data from&lt;/strong> radio buttons. Choose from a) Process b) Partner process c) Data source. Depending on which option you choose go to the relevant area to read more on &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner process&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The second option &lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> has 3 radio buttons associated with it a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user. TO COME BACK TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The third option &lt;strong>Connect to List Widget&lt;/strong> allows you to choose if this widget should connect to List widgets you have created for this dashboard page. Choose from a) Yes or b) No if you want to connect the widgets. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then click into the List Widget field and choose from previously created list widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/connecttolist.png" alt="Connect to List widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="pages/chartviewfields.md">Chart view fields&lt;/a> to read about options in the right-hand pane of this dialog box to make changes to your chart like size, labels and adding a chart legend.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished choosing options, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/processdata2.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user - TO COME BACK TO&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Partner Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partnerprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose from a pre-configured Partner who has created the process you are interested in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user - TO COME BACK TO&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Data source, then click on the &lt;strong>Select data source&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Selecting a data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will be directed to different data sources where you can search in the &lt;strong>datasource tree&lt;/strong> search box or drill down to the data source you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Select data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Conditions</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/conditions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/conditions/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Conditions allow you to make forms and dashboards fully dynamic. They are easy to configure in the Kianda platform, using natural language to create triggers for rule execution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conditions can be applied to &lt;a href="pages/tile.md">Tile&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="pages/list.md">List&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="pages/chart.md">Chart&lt;/a> dashboard widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure you in &lt;strong>Edit mode&lt;/strong> on your dashboard page by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu. Click hen click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton_frame.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button for any Tile, List or Chart widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditions.png" alt="Conditions button">appears in the dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add a conditions group&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addconditions.png" alt="Add conditions button"> button to add a condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/editconditions.png" alt="Edit conditions">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click into the first empty field to choose a field to filter on, this can be a &lt;strong>Common field&lt;/strong> or a &lt;strong>Design field&lt;/strong> as found in a form. Click on the + symbol to drill down to the relevant fields to use. Click on a field to use, for example the Common field, &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo;. If you want to replace the field for a different one, click on the X &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/x.png" alt="X"> beside the field name.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the operator field and choose from a relevant operator to apply, for example &lt;strong>Equals&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Contains&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Is blank&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Matches pattern&lt;/strong> and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/operator.png" alt="Condition operators">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a time-based field is chosen then a drop-down list of time-related operators become available, for example &lt;strong>Is Today&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Is Between Days&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Is Before Today&lt;/strong> and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Depending on the operator chosen, then a value field may be visible where you can either a) type in a value that you want to hone in on, or b) click into the field to drill down to a design field as found in a form. In the example below, we are looking for a particular value called &amp;lsquo;completed&amp;rsquo; against the Common field, &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/conditionapplied.png" alt="Condition applied">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Add condition&lt;/strong> to add further conditions and group together into an expression using the &lt;strong>drop-down list&lt;/strong> of Boolean operators a) And or b) Or&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/expression.png" alt="Conditions">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then add further condition groups using the &lt;strong>Add a conditions group&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addconditions.png" alt="Add conditions button"> button to add and apply the &lt;strong>radio buttons&lt;/strong> of Boolean operators a) And or b) Or to tie groups together.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Delete conditions by clicking on the Bin/Trash button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button again for the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box to apply the changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Filter widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/filter/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Link widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/link/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: LIst widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/list/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The list widget displays the instances of the selected process in a dashboard. The List widget can also be used to connect with any other dashboard widgets to display filtered items.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After creating a dashboard page, make sure you are in Edit mode, by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> at the top of the page, so the Widget menu with 7 widget types is available. Then click on the List widget &lt;img src="images/listwidget.png" alt="List widget">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addlistwidget.png" alt="Add list widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the dashboard title, for example Training Requests&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - control the size of the dashboard, choose from 1 to 12 columns in width. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a panel that is 6 columns wide, or click on the right of the blue bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> checkbox - tick this checkbox if you wish to show a header on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - determine who will see the dashboard, choose from a) Users b) Groups&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - choose from icons for deshtop, tablet, mobile, wifi and flightmode as to when the device can view the dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing the dashboard to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can then edit the widget to display certain fields from your form, that relates to the data you are interested in. Go to &lt;a href="#configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton_frame.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To re-edit the title, colour scheme or other options in Step 2, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box options, allowing you to make changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the widget at any stage, click on the &lt;strong>Bin&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="images/bin.png" alt="Bin button"> beside the cog button, and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> to confirm that you want to delete the dashboard page or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button in a list widget you have created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton.png" alt="Chart widget edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A dialog box opens with filter options in the left-hand pane, a &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/conditions.png" alt="Conditions">in the middle of the box, and list view fields in the right-hand pane. Go to &lt;a href="pages/conditions.md">Conditions&lt;/a> to read more about conditions you can apply to data and go to &lt;a href="pages/listviewfields.md">List view fields&lt;/a> to read more about how to apply fields to your list view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listconfig.png" alt="Editing options">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first option to choose is where the data should originate from using the &lt;strong>Data from&lt;/strong> radio buttons. Choose from a) Process b) Partner process c) Data source. Depending on which option you choose go to the relevant area to read more on &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner process&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once a data source is chosen, then there are a number of other options available, see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished choosing options, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/processdata2.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user - TO COME BACK TO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For all other available options see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Partner Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partnerprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose from a pre-configured Partner who has created the process you are interested in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user - TO COME BACK TO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For all other available options see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Data source, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dataprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Select data source&lt;/strong>. You will be directed to different data sources where you can search in the &lt;strong>datasource tree&lt;/strong> search box or drill down to the data source you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Select data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Data source filter&lt;/strong> TO COME BACK TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For all other available options see &lt;a href="#filter-options">Filter options&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="filter-options">Filter options&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once you have chosen where the dashboard data will come from then there are a number of other options available.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable sorting&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable sorting in the dashboard&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable filtering&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable filtering in the dashboard&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable search&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable a search in the dashboard&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable &amp;ldquo;Load more&amp;rdquo; mode&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to enable more data records to be visible. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you can decide on what text should appear on screen, by typing the text in the &lt;strong>Load more button text&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter a number in &lt;strong>Items per page&lt;/strong> for the number items you wish to load at a time. The default value is &amp;lsquo;20&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show &amp;lsquo;Add process&amp;rsquo; button&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to Add process to your dashboard. TO COME BACK TO If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then you can decide on what text should appear on screen, by typing the text in the &lt;strong>&amp;lsquo;Add process&amp;rsquo; button text&lt;/strong> field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, the process used to generate the data is added, click on &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> beside the Add &amp;lsquo;Process Name&amp;rsquo; by default if you don&amp;rsquo;t wish to add the input process.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show delete button&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to add a Delete button to your dashboard. If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, then the option &lt;strong>Enable bulk delete&lt;/strong> appears allowing you to choose a) Yes or b) No to enable bulk deletion of records.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable show history&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to show the history of the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable data export&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Yes or b) No if you wish to allow data export.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sort by - click into the Sort By field and choose from options a) Common fields or b) fields within a form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Common fields&lt;/strong> are fields commonly used in dashboards such as &amp;lsquo;Created&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Status&amp;rsquo; or choose from a field within a form by clicking and drilling down to the field name that you want to sort by, for example a text box field called &amp;lsquo;Name&amp;rsquo; in a form called &amp;lsquo;Training Request&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When a field is chosen then the options for &lt;strong>Sort Direction&lt;/strong> appear as either a) Ascending or b) Descending.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Then by&lt;/strong> - TO COME BACK TO&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable empty list template&lt;/strong> - click on a) Yes or b) No to enable TO COME BACK TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="pages/listviewfields.md">List view fields&lt;/a> to read about options in the right-hand pane of this dialog box on how to choose fields to filter data.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Richtext widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/richtext/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Tile widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/tile/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The tile widget allows you to display a count of instances. This is a really useful way to showcase whole numbers for example total budget requested through Purchase Orders, or the amount of customer queries solved in a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After creating a dashboard page, make sure you are in Edit mode, by clicking on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="C:%5CKianda%5Cdocs-dev%5Cpages%5Ctile.assets%5Cedit.png" alt="Edit button"> at the top of the page, so the Widget menu with 7 widget types is available. Then click on the Tile widget &lt;img src="images/tile.png" alt="Tile widget button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Add widget&lt;/strong> dialog box opens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/addtilewidget.png" alt="Add tile widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the dashboard title, for example Type of Training&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Layout columns&lt;/strong> - control the size of the dashboard, choose from 1 to 12 columns in width. For example click half-way across the blue bar to create a panel that is 6 columns wide, or click on the right of the blue bar to create a column that is 12 columns wide.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Colour scheme&lt;/strong> - choose from Navy, Green, Blue, Amber, Red or White Colours for your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show header&lt;/strong> checkbox - tick this checkbox if you wish to show a header on your dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Visible to&lt;/strong> - determine who will see the dashboard, choose from a) Users b) Groups&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Device visibility&lt;/strong> - choose from icons for deshtop, tablet, mobile, wifi and flightmode as to when the device can view the dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/devicevisibility.png" alt="Device visibility">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing the dashboard to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can then edit the widget to display certain fields from your form, that relates to the data you are interested in. Go to &lt;a href="#configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/a> to find out more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished making edits, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/save.png" alt="Save button"> in the top menu to ensure your dashboard changes are saved and you see a pop-up message &lt;strong>Page saved successfully&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make further changes later on, click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit.png" alt="Edit button"> in the top menu and then click on the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penbutton_frame.png" alt="Pen button in a widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To re-edit the title, colour scheme or other options in Step 2, click on the &lt;strong>Settings&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/cog.png" alt="Settings button">and the &lt;strong>Edit widget&lt;/strong> dialog box options, allowing you to make changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the widget at any stage, click on the &lt;strong>Bin&lt;/strong> icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bin.png" alt="Bin button"> beside the cog button, and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> to confirm that you want to delete the dashboard page or click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="configure-your-widget">Configure your widget&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Update configuration&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button in a tile widget you have created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edittile.png" alt="Tile widget edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A dialog box opens with filter options in the left-hand pane, a &lt;strong>Conditions&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="C:%5CKianda%5Cdocs-dev%5Cpages%5Ctile.assets%5Cconditions.png" alt="Conditions">in the middle of the box, and tile view fields in the right-hand pane. Go to &lt;a href="pages/conditions.md">Conditions&lt;/a> to read more about conditions you can apply to data, and go to &lt;a href="pages/tileviewfields.md">Tile view fields&lt;/a> to read more about changing how a tile looks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edittilebox.png" alt="Editing a tile widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first option on the left is to choose is where the data should originate from using the &lt;strong>Data from&lt;/strong> radio buttons. Choose from a) Process b) Partner process c) Data source. Depending on which option you choose go to the relevant area to read more on &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner process&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The second option &lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> has 3 radio buttons associated with it a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user. TO COME BACK TO.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The third option &lt;strong>Show decimals&lt;/strong> allows you to choose if a decimal point is used in the number displayed. Choose from a) Yes or b) No if you want to only show a whole number.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fourth option &lt;strong>Connect to List widget&lt;/strong> allows you to choose if this widget should connect to List widgets you have created for this dashboard page. Choose from a) Yes or b) No if you want to connect the widgets. If you click on &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> then click into the List Widget field and choose from previously created list widgets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/connecttolist.png" alt="Connect to List widget">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="pages/tileviewfields.md">Tile view fields&lt;/a> to read about options in the right-hand pane of this dialog box to make changes to your tile like icons and colours.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>When you are finished choosing options, click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-process">Choosing data from a Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/processdata2.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user - TO COME BACK TO&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-partner-process">Choosing data from a Partner Process&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Partner Process, then the options below become available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/partnerprocess_resized.png" alt="Choosing data from a Process">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Choose from the following options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Partner&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose from a pre-configured Partner who has created the process you are interested in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Business process&lt;/strong> - click into the field to choose a process which will be the input for the dashboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show processes&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Matching condition b) Matching condition and assigned to current user c) Matching condition and created by current user&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="choosing-data-from-a-data-source">Choosing data from a Data source&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you choose data from a Data source, then click on the &lt;strong>Select data source&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Selecting a data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will be directed to different data sources where you can search in the &lt;strong>datasource tree&lt;/strong> search box or drill down to the data source you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/selectdatasource.png" alt="Select data source">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Walkthrough widget</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/pages/walkthrough/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>