<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Getting started</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Welcome to Kianda</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Kianda platform is a modern &lt;a href="#kianda-is-a-no-code-and-low-code-development-platform">&lt;strong>low-code&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>no-code&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>development platform&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> providing anyone, including those without coding experience, the ability to digitise business &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong> and create beautiful, mobile-ready web applications. You can also use Kianda to make &lt;strong>dashboards&lt;/strong> to monitor how your processes are performing and gain key insights to improve your business. And you can &lt;strong>customise&lt;/strong> all of this the way you want to - no developer needed. However, if you are a developer, you can use the platform to build ambitious web-based business applications of any kind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Kianda platform provides an ideal interface for &lt;strong>rapid prototyping&lt;/strong> and delivering outcomes quickly. But don&amp;rsquo;t just take our word for it, see what our customers have to say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>What is possible with Kianda: DEME example&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;video width="100%" style="width:100%" controls>
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/deme_narration.mp4">
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/source>
&lt;/video>
&lt;p>The Kianda platform can quickly deliver amazing results to any digital project - from task automation to document generation - following industry best practices. So grab a cup of coffee and learn more about Kianda.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kianda-is-a-no-code-and-low-code-development-platform">Kianda is a no-code and low-code development platform&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kianda saves your organisation time and resources. Following a short onboarding, any employee can be assigned to build web applications for your business, without the need for any coding experience. &lt;strong>No-code&lt;/strong> literally means just that - you don&amp;rsquo;t need to know how to code to build digital processes in Kianda. Anyone is empowered to create. Using Kianda, you can create a prototype quickly and simply in an easy-to-use interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those who have coding experience, Kianda&amp;rsquo;s open, extensible architecture allows a &lt;strong>low-code&lt;/strong> approach, meaning you can use the graphical user interface to extend the range of applications to create what you want, using your own code. This type of reusability, leveraging existing templates to build applications, reduces turnaround time and improves organisational productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flexible nature of Kianda allows custom-coding and no-coding development, providing the optimum solution for your business.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="if-you-are-ready-to-discover-more-about-kianda-lets-get-started--idea-iconimages18png">&lt;strong>If you are ready to discover more about Kianda, let&amp;rsquo;s get started&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="to-learn-how-to-start-using-kianda-go-to">To learn how to start using Kianda, go to:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/logging-in/">&lt;strong>Logging in&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you want to use Kianda for no-code development, then follow the steps below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/one.png" alt="1"> &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/plan-your-process/">&lt;strong>Plan your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/two.png" alt="2"> &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/">&lt;strong>Design and build your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/three.png" alt="3"> &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/">&lt;strong>Publish your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Logging in to Kianda</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/logging-in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/logging-in/</guid><description>
&lt;p>If your organisation already has a login, go to your given Kianda login page. If not, sign up for a free trial by going to &lt;a href="https://portal.kianda.com/public/signup">https://portal.kianda.com/public/signup&lt;/a>. You will be prompted to confirm your email address and you can then login. The Kianda platform runs in the cloud, so you only need a web browser and can use any mobile device to login.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you login you will have access to the Kianda &lt;strong>workspace&lt;/strong> where you can build end-to-end business processes, connect to data sources and view the results in real-time data dashboards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Kianda workspace&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/workspace4.gif" alt="User interface">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The layout of the Kianda workspace is as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Company logo&lt;/strong> - the top left-hand corner is reserved for uploading company logos. If you click on the &lt;strong>Collapse navigation&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/navigation_frame_copy.png" alt="Collapse navigation button"> you will see the collapsed version of the company logo and collapsed side menu, giving you more real estate in the central view panel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Side menu&lt;/strong> - Beneath the logo is the left-hand pane, the side menu, containing all the key functions to create and manage your business processes. From this menu you will start &lt;strong>creating&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>processes&lt;/strong>. In the side menu, under &lt;strong>More&lt;/strong>, there are links to get &lt;strong>Help&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Support&lt;/strong>, and give &lt;strong>Feedback&lt;/strong>. From this menu you can also develop your own widgets, see &lt;a href="getting-started/welcome/low_code.md#how-to-get-started-with-developer">Developer&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Quick Action menu&lt;/strong> - the top right-hand menu bar contains shortcuts to keep you updated and allows you to &lt;strong>add dashboard pages&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Main view&lt;/strong> - the central panel is the main view for any of the functions chosen from the side menu. Here you can &lt;strong>view and edit&lt;/strong> processes and dashboards.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="getting-started/logging_in/personalise_workspace.md">Personalise your workspace&lt;/a> to find out to change the look and feel as well as regional settings for your workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Learn how to &lt;a href="getting-started/create-first-process/">&lt;strong>create your first Kianda process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, then follow the steps below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/one.png" alt="1"> &lt;a href="getting-started/create-first-process/plan_process.md">&lt;strong>Plan your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/two.png" alt="2"> &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/">&lt;strong>Design and build your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/three.png" alt="3"> &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/">&lt;strong>Publish your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have coding experience and want to delve straight into how you can use Kianda to create your own widgets, go to &lt;a href="getting-started/welcome/low_code.md#how-to-get-started-with-developer">&lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> to learn more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="user-tip-target-iconimages05png">User tip &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/05.png" alt="Target icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Take a look at our series of short &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/how-to/">&lt;strong>How to videos&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo; designed to help you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="to-return-to-the-previous-pages-click-on-the-links-below--idea-iconimages10png">&lt;strong>To return to the previous pages click on the links below&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/10.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/">Getting started guide&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/welcome/">Welcome to Kianda&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Create your first Kianda process</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/</guid><description>
&lt;p>You can create an end-to-end process quickly and simply in Kianda and use this prototype to develop your ideas through an iterative process. This &lt;strong>agile approach&lt;/strong> results in significantly faster development time, that is cost effective and reduces risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Agile development cycle&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/agile.png" alt="No-code agile approach">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main phases of an agile project are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Planning - this involves determining the scope of the project, what is it you want to achieve and what end-users will be supported and how. The outcome will be a list of requirements that can be adjusted as the process is developed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design - this involves construction of a draft of your product. Previewing the draft is included in this phase and there may be several rounds of revisions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Launch - this phase includes piloting the product with a number of users, monitoring results, getting feedback and then releasing the product including all related documentation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Mapping these phases to process creation in Kianda, results in three main steps: &lt;strong>Plan &amp;gt; Design &amp;gt; Publish&lt;/strong>. Each step contains three substeps as outlined below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-your-kianda-processes-in-an-agile-way">Creating your Kianda processes in an agile way&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Three steps to create a process&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/flowchart.png" alt="Kianda process creation">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using Kianda allows you to leverage the agile development process to maximum effect:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Plan&lt;/strong> - our documentation will guide you when it&amp;rsquo;s time for you to capture your requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/greena.png" alt="A"> What &lt;strong>forms&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>fields&lt;/strong> do you need in your process based on what you want to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/greenb.png" alt="B"> What &lt;strong>rules&lt;/strong> can be applied to create smart, automated processes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/greenc.png" alt="C"> Who needs &lt;strong>access&lt;/strong> to the forms as a user and form owner? Review these questions as you modify the process.
&lt;/br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Design&lt;/strong> - you can create drafts processes and restore to earlier versions allowing you complete control over production.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/a.png" alt="A"> Processes are made up of interactive &lt;strong>forms&lt;/strong> which you can create at the click of a button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/b.png" alt="B"> Forms connect to your &lt;strong>datasources&lt;/strong> so as your organisation changes, your processes respond accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/c.png" alt="C"> Use the in-built &lt;strong>previewer&lt;/strong> to preview and test your design, then save new versions as you modify design.
&lt;/br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> - expand access to published processes as you become comfortable with the design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bluea.png" alt="A"> Allow individual user, group or partner access in order to &lt;strong>deploy&lt;/strong> the solution in a controlled way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/blueb.png" alt="B"> View key metrics in process &lt;strong>dashboards&lt;/strong> to get insights into how to improve the process and the organisation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/bluec.png" alt="C"> &lt;strong>Launch&lt;/strong> and release the process, including documentation which can feed into future development projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you are familiar with the development cycle, you can start to develop your Kianda process following the steps below:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/one.png" alt="1"> &lt;a href="getting-started/create-first-process/plan_process.md">&lt;strong>Plan your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/two.png" alt="2"> &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/design-and-build/">&lt;strong>Design and build your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/three.png" alt="3"> &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/getting-started/create-first-process/publish-your-process/">&lt;strong>Publish your process&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have coding experience and want to delve straight into how you can use Kianda to create your own widgets, go to &lt;a href="getting-started/welcome/low_code.md#how-to-get-started-with-developer">&lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> to learn more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="to-return-to-the-previous-pages-click-on-the-links-below--idea-iconimages10png">&lt;strong>To return to the previous pages click on the links below&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/10.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="getting-started/">&lt;strong>Getting started guide&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="getting-started/logging_in/">Logging in to Kianda&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="getting-started/logging_in/personalise_workspace.md">Personalise your workspace&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>