<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Input controls</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/</link><description>Recent content in Input controls on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Date control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/date/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Date controls&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Date fields&lt;/strong> can be inserted in a form when you want a user to be able to input a date and time by using a date and time picker. For example, in a Training Request form, you may want the user to select the date and time of the training course they want to attend.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process. Then select the form within that process that you want to add the field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> by clicking on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu, then select &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> to view the range of Input controls and click on &lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong>. A date field will be added to your form with the default title of &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Date 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; and a pop-up message will say &amp;lsquo;Field added&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Date_Field_Added.jpg" alt="List inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Date field has a small calendar icon on the right hand side - when the user clicks on this icon a calendar is displayed, allowing them to select a date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Date_Field_Expanded.jpg" alt="List inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-date-fields">How to edit, move and delete Date fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) and then click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Select_Date_field_to_edit.jpg" alt="Select date field to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from a range of options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Edit_Date_Field_dialog_box.jpg" alt="Edit date field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within the &lt;strong>Edit date field dialog box&lt;/strong> include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - you can change the title of the date field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - you can insert help text a user can view when completing the date field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display format&lt;/strong> - you can choose whether the date field shows the date only or the date and time&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Adjust to user timezone&lt;/strong> - you can select this if you want the date field to adjust to the time zone of the form user&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Set default date onload&lt;/strong> - if you choose &amp;lsquo;Yes&amp;rsquo;, this means that a value will automatically be put in the date field (like a date stamp) when a user fills out the form and two additional options will appear in the dialog box:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Default date&lt;/strong> - the option to choose the default date that will be automatically inserted in the form. You can choose from &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Now&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Today&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; (which inserts today&amp;rsquo;s date and a time of 00:00 midnight) or &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Relative from now&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong> (you can insert the date you want to use, in terms of the number of days, hours and minutes from now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Always set date even if not empty&lt;/strong> - the option to have the default date you choose inserted in the date field, even if the field is not empty.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable native picker on mobile&lt;/strong> - you can choose to allow users who are completing the date field on a mobile phone to use the default pop-up date picker associated with their mobile phone&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong>, simply select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button"> and drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it to within your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Move_Date_Field_Drag_Handle.jpg" alt="Date field drag handle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> from your form, simply select the field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">), click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-date-field-properties">How to edit Date field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the field title or field drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Date_Field_Properties_new.jpg" alt="Field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> titled &lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong> has been selected in a form called &amp;lsquo;Expense Report&amp;rsquo; and the Field properties associated with this field include its Title, that its title will be shown in the form (the &amp;lsquo;Show title&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), that this will not be a field users are required to complete (the &amp;lsquo;Required&amp;rsquo; checkbox is not selected), that this field will be enabled for users to complete (the &amp;lsquo;Enabled&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), and that this field will be visible to form users (the &amp;lsquo;Visible&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about &lt;strong>Date controls&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Input fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/">File upload control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/">Number control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">Table control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">Textbox control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/">Toggle control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/">User picker control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: File upload control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>File upload controls&lt;/strong> (fields) can be inserted in a form if you want form users to be able to upload a file or files. File upload fields can also be useful if you want a file to be generated from the information entered in a form or if you want a file to be sent as part of your process - see &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/">Rules&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, in an Inspection process, you may want the user (an inspector) to be able to upload the details of their inspection as a PDF file or photos as they complete an Inspection Form; or you may want the Kianda system to generate a report based on the information in the Inspection Form and to email this as a PDF file to a supervisor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process. Then select the form within that process that you want to add the field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong> by clicking on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu, then select &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> to view the range of Input controls and click on &lt;strong>File&lt;/strong>. A &lt;strong>New field - File&lt;/strong> dialog box will open with a range of options you can choose from for your new File upload field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/New_File_Field_dialog_box.jpg" alt="Edit file upload field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options available in the &lt;strong>New field - File&lt;/strong> dialog box include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong>: You can change the name of the File upload field from the default &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>File 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong>: You can insert text to help the form user to complete the File upload field - if you add help text, a question mark &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Help_icon.jpg" alt="Help text icon"> icon will appear next to the field title and, if the user clicks on this, they will see the help text you have inserted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Upload_Help_Text.jpg" alt="File upload help text example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Save location&lt;/strong>: This is the location the file will be saved to. When you click on the &lt;strong>Destination&lt;/strong> button, a &lt;strong>Select datasource&lt;/strong> dialog box opens in which you can choose where you want the file(s) to be saved to:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Upload_Select_Datasource.jpg" alt="Select datasource dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can choose to save the file or files to Kianda or to another external data source.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Open file behaviour&lt;/strong>: You can choose whether the file is downloaded or opens in an internet browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow file override&lt;/strong>: You can choose whether or not to allow file override.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow remove file&lt;/strong>: If you select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, another option appears - &lt;strong>Remove and delete file&lt;/strong>: if you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, when the file is removed, it will also be deleted from the location where it was stored; if you choose &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong>, then only the reference to the file is removed from the form.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Allow uploading multiple files&lt;/strong>: Choose &lt;strong>No&lt;/strong> to only allow the user to upload one file or choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to allow the user to upload multiple files.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>File name options&lt;/strong>: Choose whether to keep the original file name, to have the file name auto generated by the system, or to be based on a form field. If you choose &lt;strong>From form field&lt;/strong>, another option appears - &lt;strong>File name field&lt;/strong> - and you click in the blank field to choose the file name field you want the file name to be:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Name_Field.jpg" alt="File name field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>File extension&lt;/strong>: You can set/limit the type of file(s) that can be uploaded by inserting a specific file type. For example, if you insert &lt;strong>.pdf&lt;/strong> in the File extension box, when the user browses for the file to attach, the file type will automatically be set to .pdf. If you want to allow any type of file to be attached, leave this option blank.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable media capture&lt;/strong>: If you choose &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong>, this enables the user to capture media to upload - on a mobile device, when the user clicks on the Upload button their camera/video recorder will open (depending on whether you&amp;rsquo;ve selected the file extension to be image or video).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Button text&lt;/strong>: By default, the File upload icon has the text &lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong>, but you can change this here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Button icon&lt;/strong>: By default, the file upload icon is &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Upload_Icon.jpg" alt="File upload icon"> but you can change this by clicking the Button icon drop-down menu and choosing a different icon from the large range of icons available.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable background upload&lt;/strong>: Select this checkbox to enable files to be uploaded using a background operation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable chunked upload&lt;/strong>: Select this checkbox to upload files using resumable chunks. This option can be useful if the file size is likely to be large or the network speed is likely to be slow.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show uploaded files count&lt;/strong>: Select &lt;strong>Yes&lt;/strong> to show the number of uploaded files.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once you complete the &lt;strong>New field - File&lt;/strong> dialog box and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong>, a new &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong> is added to your form, with the name you inserted as the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> in the dialog box (by default the title is &lt;strong>File 1&lt;/strong> unless you change it).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In the example of our Inspection Form, the new File upload field (titled &lt;strong>Upload photos&lt;/strong>) added to the form could look like this when a user views it on a mobile phone (to see how your form or field will look on a mobile, view it in &lt;strong>Mobile preview&lt;/strong> by using the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> option which can be opened by clicking the play button icon &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview">):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Upload_Example_Mobile.jpg" alt="File upload example mobile phone">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-file-upload-fields">How to edit, move and delete File upload fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) and then click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Upload_Edit.jpg" alt="Select file upload file to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field - File&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from the same range of options as appear in the &lt;strong>New field - File&lt;/strong> dialog box (as already discussed in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Upload_Edit_Field_dialog_box.jpg" alt="Edit date field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can make any changes you wish in this dialog box and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong>, simply select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button"> and drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it to within your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Upload_File_Move_draghandle.jpg" alt="Date field drag handle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong> from your form, simply select the field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">), click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-file-upload-field-properties">How to edit File upload field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the field title or field drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/File_Upload_Field_Properties.jpg" alt="Field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, a &lt;strong>File upload field&lt;/strong> titled &lt;strong>Upload Photos&lt;/strong> has been selected in a form called &amp;lsquo;Inspection Form&amp;rsquo; and the Field properties associated with this field include its Title, that its title will be shown in the form (the &amp;lsquo;Show title&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), that this is a mandatory field that users must complete (the &amp;lsquo;Required&amp;rsquo; checkbox is selected and there is a red star next to the field name in the form), that this field will be enabled for users to complete (the &amp;lsquo;Enabled&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), and that this field will be visible to form users (the &amp;lsquo;Visible&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about the &lt;strong>File upload control&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Input fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/date/">Date control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/">Number control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">Table control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">Textbox control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/">Toggle control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/">User picker control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Number control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: List control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>List fields&lt;/strong> (controls) can be manually entered into a form or can be linked to from an external site like SharePoint. There are different display options - from dropdown lists to checklists - as well as other options (like the ability to make a list field mandatory for a user to complete).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, you could insert a list field in your form that will show a drop-down list of Types of Training that is maintained on SharePoint. The advantage of linking to an external data source like this is that your list will stay up-to-date with any changes made to the list on SharePoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process. Then select the form within that process that you want to add the field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible). If you want to add the List field to a panel within your form, first select the panel by clicking on it and then add the &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the new &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong> by clicking on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu, then select &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> to view the range of Input controls and click on &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong>. A &lt;strong>New field - List&lt;/strong> dialog box will open with a range of options you can choose from for your new List field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_New_dialog_box.jpg" alt="New list field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options available in the &lt;strong>New field - List&lt;/strong> dialog box include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - You can change the name of the List field from the default title &lt;strong>List 1&lt;/strong>. For example, if you are working on a Training Request form, you may want to insert a List field to contain the types of training and may choose to title this &amp;lsquo;Type of Training&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - This is a unique name for the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - You can insert text to help the form user to complete the List field. If you add help text, a question mark &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Help_icon.jpg" alt="Help text icon"> icon will appear next to the field title and, if the user clicks on this, they will see the help text you have inserted. In this example, the list field is titled &amp;lsquo;Type of Training&amp;rsquo; and has associated help text:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Help_Text.jpg" alt="List field help text example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong> - You have three main options in terms of the source of the choices that will appear in your List field:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>​ a) &lt;strong>Entered manually&lt;/strong>
​ b) &lt;strong>Form data&lt;/strong>
​ c) &lt;strong>Data source&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ We will look at each of these three list source options in turn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you select the &lt;strong>Entered manually&lt;/strong> checkbox, you must then manually type the choices you want to appear in your list into the &lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong> box. Three default choices are shown - simply replace these with the choices you want to appear in your list (keeping the same format of one choice per line). You can insert more than three choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_List_Source_Manually.jpg" alt="Manually entered list">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you select the &lt;strong>Form data&lt;/strong> checkbox (so the source of your list options is a form field), then the box under &lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong> will now show the instruction &amp;lsquo;Select a form field&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; and two further options will appear below this - &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong>. Click into the &lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong> box and select the form field you wish to use as your &lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong>. Then choose a &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong> (the field used to display values) and a &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_List_Source_Form_Data.jpg" alt="List field list source form data">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you select the &lt;strong>Data source&lt;/strong> checkbox (to use an external data source as the source for the choices to appear in your list) a range of new options appears below the &lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong> radio boxes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_List_Source_Datasource.jpg" alt="List field list source datasource">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasource.png" alt="Data source button"> to open the &lt;strong>Select datasource&lt;/strong> dialog box and choose the data source you want to connect to as the source for your list options - for example, SharePoint. For more information on how to connect to data sources in Kianda, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Data connectors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Select_Data_Source.jpg" alt="List field select data source dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve selected a data source, click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> - a range of new options will now be shown below the &lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> button in the &lt;strong>New field - List&lt;/strong> dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select the &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and a field to &lt;strong>Sort by&lt;/strong> (the &amp;lsquo;Sort by&amp;rsquo; option appears once you&amp;rsquo;ve selected a data source). Once you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen a field to sort by, an additional option - &lt;strong>Direction&lt;/strong> - appears, enabling you to choose to sort values in &lt;strong>Ascending&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Descending&lt;/strong> order. The &lt;strong>Enable offline cache&lt;/strong> option will make the list data available when the user is offline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Datasource_Options.jpg" alt="List field Data source options example">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>Edit conditions&lt;/strong> button if you want to add a condition to your List field. To learn more about applying conditions, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/general/add-conditions/">Conditions&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve selected your &lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong> and the various options associated with it, complete the remaining options in the &lt;strong>New field - List&lt;/strong> dialog box:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Display format&lt;/strong> - You can choose to have your list field appear as either a Drop-down list, a Radio list, Multi-select or a Checkbox list.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>By default, the &lt;strong>Dropdown list&lt;/strong> radio button is selected, along with two additional options - &lt;strong>Filter mode&lt;/strong> (you can choose either &amp;lsquo;Starts With&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Contains&amp;rsquo;) and &lt;strong>Enable native selector on mobile&lt;/strong> (so a user completing the list field on their mobile phone can use the default list selector on it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Display_Format.jpg" alt="Dropdown list display format">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose &lt;strong>Radio list&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Checkbox list&lt;/strong> you can choose a &lt;strong>List display position&lt;/strong> of either Vertical or Horizontal.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>Once you complete the &lt;strong>New field - List&lt;/strong> dialog box and click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button, a new &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong> is added to your form, with the name you inserted as the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> in the dialog box (by default, the title is &lt;strong>List 1&lt;/strong> unless you change it).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If we take the example of a Training Request form with a list field that contains the different types of training a user can request, the list field (which is titled &amp;lsquo;Type of Training&amp;rsquo; and has a drop-down list format) could look like this when a user views it on their mobile phone:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Example_Mobile.jpg" alt="List field dropdown list example mobile phone">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To see how your form or field will look like on a mobile, view it in &lt;strong>Mobile preview&lt;/strong> by clicking the &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/preview.png" alt="Preview">(play icon) after first saving your changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-file-upload-fields">How to edit, move and delete File upload fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) and then click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Select_to_Edit.jpg" alt="Select file upload file to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field - List&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from the same range of options as appear in the &lt;strong>New field - List&lt;/strong> dialog box (as already discussed in &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list#how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Edit_dialog_box_example.jpg" alt="Edit date field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can make any changes you wish in this dialog box and then click &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong>, simply select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button"> and drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it to within your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Move_draghandle.jpg" alt="Date field drag handle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong> from your form, simply select the field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">), click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-list-field-properties">How to edit List field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the field title or field drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/List_Field_Field_Properties.jpg" alt="List properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, a &lt;strong>List field&lt;/strong> titled &lt;strong>Type of Training&lt;/strong> has been selected and it&amp;rsquo;s properties are displayed, including: its Title, that its Title will be shown in the form (the &amp;lsquo;Show title&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), that it will be a mandatory field for users to complete (the &amp;lsquo;Required&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked and there is a red star next to the field name in the form), that this field will be enabled for users to complete (the &amp;lsquo;Enabled&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), and that this field will be visible to form users (the &amp;lsquo;Visible&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked). The width of the field on PC and mobile is also shown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about &lt;strong>List controls&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Input fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/date/">Date control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/">File upload control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/">Number control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">Table control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">Textbox control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/">Toggle control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/">User picker control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Table control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Textbox control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Text box control&lt;/strong> is used to input text into a form for example a name or address. There are various options available when creating this field, these are explained below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to add a text box to a form - a sample video&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;video title="How to add a text box to a form" width="100%" style="width:100%" controls="controls">
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/textbox.mp4" type="video/mp4">
&lt;/video>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add the Text box to your form click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong>. The text box can also be placed within an element for example a panel, by clicking on the panel itself and then add the text box. Compare in the image below, the text box Name which is inside a panel versus Reason for the request which is outside the panel, both in the form Employee Request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxinout.png" alt="Text boxes inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To edit the Text box, click on the field itself and the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> appears allowing you to edit the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edittextbox.png" alt="Edit text box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - of the field, for example Employee Name&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - information to help the form user&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) Single line of text b) Multiple lines of text c) Rich text&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose a) Single line of text then the following additional options are visible:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Control type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Text b) Password&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Autofill type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Default b) Off c) Password d) Address e) Email f) Phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Placeholder&lt;/strong> - placeholder text that can help the user to know what to fill out in the text box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose b) Multiple lines of text then the following additional options are visible:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Control type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Text b) Password&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Autofill type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Default b) Off c) Password d) Address e) Email f) Phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Placeholder&lt;/strong> - placeholder text that can help the user to know what to fill out in the text box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Rows&lt;/strong> - the number of rows you would like for the text box&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text style&lt;/strong> - options are a) Normal b) Capitalise c) Uppercase d) Lowercase&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Max length&lt;/strong> - the maximum number of characters for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text style&lt;/strong> - options are a) Normal b) Capitalise c) Uppercase d) Lowercase&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Expression&lt;/strong> - this can be used to return a value for example Date() returns the current date and time. For a full explanation of expressions go to &lt;a href="platform/expressions.md">Expressions&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxfilled.png" alt="Example of text box options">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> when you are finished editing the field to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To move the text box, click on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="images/move.png" alt="Move button">on the text box field itself and drag it to where you want it to appear on the form, for example within a panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change the text box properties, click on the field itself and the properties pane appears on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxproperties.png" alt="Text box properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="fields/properties.md">Properties&lt;/a> to find out more about options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To save your changes to the form, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the text box, click on the field itself and then click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin or Trash icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the field name and are sure this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Toggle control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: User picker control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>user picker field&lt;/strong> provides a way to associate a user to a particular task for example to allow a form user to find their manager to approve a workflow. This is achieved by connecting your Kianda form to a data source, for example information in SharePoint, and using the user picker field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a particular user, click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>User picker&lt;/strong>. The field can also be placed within an element for example a panel, by clicking on the panel itself and then add user picker field. Compare in the image below, the field Line Manager which is inside a panel versus Department Manager which is outside the panel, both in the form Employee Request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpickerinout.png" alt="User picker field inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - of the user, for example Training Manager&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - information to help the form user&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) Single or b) Multiple&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose b) Multiple then you can choose the maximum number of users to select by clicking on the arrow or simply typing your number into the box, for example 3 users as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/maxusers.png" alt="Maximum number of users to select">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Default to current user&lt;/strong> - options to default to the current user when in edit mode are a) No or b) Yes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Member of group&lt;/strong> - select the group from your data source that the user is a member of, for example HR Managers&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Selection options&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Users b) Groups c) Partners, as many as needed&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Default selection option&lt;/strong> - choose one from a) Users b) Groups c) Partners&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show selection option menu&lt;/strong> - options are a) No or b) Yes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="Ok button"> when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you need to re-edit the user picker field, click on the field itself and the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> appears allowing you to edit the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpickeredit.png" alt="Editing the user picker field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To move the field, click on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="images/move.png" alt="Move button">on the user picker field itself and drag it to where you want it to appear on the form, for example within a panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To save your changes to the form, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the field, click on the field itself and then click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin or Trash icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the field name and are sure this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-edit-user-picker-properties">How to edit user picker properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To change the user picker field properties, click on the field itself and the properties pane appears on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpickerproperties.png" alt="User picker field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong>, User picker, is shown along with the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> of the field, in the example above Training Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within properties are as follows, check the checkbox to implement:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show Title&lt;/strong> - show the title of the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - make this field mandatory for users to use&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - the field is enabled for users to use&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - the field is visible to users&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - change the width of the field by clicking on the bar in the Layout box until you see the desired size. Click on the arrow beside Layout to see the Mobile Layout and click on the bar to change the width of the text box for mobile use.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxsize.png" alt="Changing text box width">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> - rules for input fields are covered in &lt;a href="rules/README.md">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>