<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Input controls</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/</link><description>Recent content in Input controls on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Date control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/date/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Date controls&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Date fields&lt;/strong> can be inserted in a form when you want a user to be able to input a date and time by using a date and time picker. For example, in a Training Request form, you may want the user to select the date and time of the training course they want to attend.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> to a form, first open the relevant process. Then select the form within that process that you want to add the field to (so that the &lt;strong>Edit Form&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit form button"> is visible).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Insert the &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> by clicking on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> in the left-hand pane to expand the Controls menu, then select &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> to view the range of Input controls and click on &lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong>. A date field will be added to your form with the default title of &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Date 1&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; and a pop-up message will say &amp;lsquo;Field added&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Date_Field_Added.jpg" alt="List inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Date field has a small calendar icon on the right hand side - when the user clicks on this icon a calendar is displayed, allowing them to select a date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Date_Field_Expanded.jpg" alt="List inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-move-and-delete-date-fields">How to edit, move and delete Date fields&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To edit a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by either clicking on the field title or on the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) and then click on the &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> button (Pen icon) &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Edit field button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Select_Date_field_to_edit.jpg" alt="Select date field to edit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Edit field&lt;/strong> dialog box will open, enabling you to choose from a range of options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Edit_Date_Field_dialog_box.jpg" alt="Edit date field dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within the &lt;strong>Edit date field dialog box&lt;/strong> include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - you can change the title of the date field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - you can insert help text a user can view when completing the date field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display format&lt;/strong> - you can choose whether the date field shows the date only or the date and time&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Adjust to user timezone&lt;/strong> - you can select this if you want the date field to adjust to the time zone of the form user&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Set default date onload&lt;/strong> - if you choose &amp;lsquo;Yes&amp;rsquo;, this means that a value will automatically be put in the date field (like a date stamp) when a user fills out the form and two additional options will appear in the dialog box:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Default date&lt;/strong> - the option to choose the default date that will be automatically inserted in the form. You can choose from &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Now&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Today&lt;/strong>&amp;rsquo; (which inserts today&amp;rsquo;s date and a time of 00:00 midnight) or &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong>Relative from now&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong> (you can insert the date you want to use, in terms of the number of days, hours and minutes from now.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Always set date even if not empty&lt;/strong> - the option to have the default date you choose inserted in the date field, even if the field is not empty.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable native picker on mobile&lt;/strong> - you can choose to allow users who are completing the date field on a mobile phone to use the default pop-up date picker associated with their mobile phone&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To move a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong>, simply select the field&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button"> and drag and drop the field wherever you want to move it to within your form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Move_Date_Field_Drag_Handle.jpg" alt="Date field drag handle">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To delete a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> from your form, simply select the field (by either clicking on the field&amp;rsquo;s name or its &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">), click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-edit-date-field-properties">How to edit Date field properties&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To view or edit the field properties associated with a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong>, select the field (by clicking on the field title or field drag handle button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/draghandlewhite_frame.png" alt="Drag handle button">) - the &lt;strong>Field properties&lt;/strong> menu will appear in the right-hand pane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Date_Field_Properties_new.jpg" alt="Field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the example shown here, a &lt;strong>Date field&lt;/strong> titled &lt;strong>Date&lt;/strong> has been selected in a form called &amp;lsquo;Expense Report&amp;rsquo; and the Field properties associated with this field include its Title, that its title will be shown in the form (the &amp;lsquo;Show title&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), that this will not be a field users are required to complete (the &amp;lsquo;Required&amp;rsquo; checkbox is not selected), that this field will be enabled for users to complete (the &amp;lsquo;Enabled&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked), and that this field will be visible to form users (the &amp;lsquo;Visible&amp;rsquo; checkbox is ticked).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To learn more about the different options within the Field properties menu, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/properties#field-properties">Field Properties&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="saving-changes-and-version-history">Saving changes and version history&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Make sure to save any changes you make by clicking on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save">. You will always have the option to revert back to previous versions of your form by clicking the &lt;strong>Design Version History&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/version8.png" alt="Version button"> button in the top right corner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve learned about &lt;strong>Date controls&lt;/strong>, find out more about the other types of &lt;strong>Input fields&lt;/strong> you can add to a Kianda process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/">File upload control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/">List control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/">Number control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/">Table control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/">Textbox control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/">Toggle control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/">User picker control&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: File upload control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/file-upload/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: List control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/list/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lists&lt;/strong> can be manually entered into a form or linked from an external site like SharePoint, for example a list of Types of Training. There are different display options from dropdown lists to checklists and the ability to make lists mandatory for users to choose in a form amongst other options.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add the List field to your form click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>List&lt;/strong>. The text box can also be placed within an element for example a panel, by clicking on the panel itself and then add the list. Compare in the image below, the list Type of Training which is inside a panel versus Reason for the request which is outside the panel, both in the form Employee Request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listinsideout.png" alt="List inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The New field - List box appears, allowing you different editing options. The options are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - the Title of the field, for example Type of Training, a list of different types of training in an organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - information to help the form user&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>List source&lt;/strong> - options are a) Entered manually b) Form data c) Data source, for example&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose a) Entered manually, you must type in your list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/manuallist.png" alt="Manually entered list">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose b) Form data ?[TO COME BACK TO]? then you must choose a &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, the field used to display values and &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> [TO COME BACK TO]?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose c) Data source then click on the &lt;strong>Datasource&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="images/datasource.png" alt="Data source button"> to connect to different data sources for example SharePoint. For information on how to connect to a data source please see &lt;a href="connectors/ReadME.md">Data connectors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you select a data source, select the &lt;strong>Display field&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Value field&lt;/strong> and field to Sort by. You can sort values in &lt;strong>Ascending&lt;/strong> or &lt;strong>Descending&lt;/strong> order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/datasourceops.png" alt="Data source list options">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other options include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable offline cache&lt;/strong> - Yes or No&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>List items limit&lt;/strong> (default is 50)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Display format&lt;/strong> - options are a) Dropdown list b) Radio list c) Multi select d) Checkbox list&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose a) Dropdown list then you have the additional options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Filter mode&lt;/strong> - the choice is a) Starts with and b) Contains&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Enable native selector on mobile&lt;/strong> - options are a) Yes or b) No&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dropdownoptions.png" alt="Dropdown list display format">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you choose b) Radio list or d) Checkbox list then you have an option:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>List display position&lt;/strong> - the choice is a) Horizontal and b) Vertical&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To move the list, click on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/move.png" alt="Move button">on the list field itself and drag it to where you want it to appear on the form, for example within a panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change list properties, click on the field itself and the properties pane appears on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listproperties.png" alt="List properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="field/properties.md">Properties&lt;/a> to find out more about options.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To save your changes to the form, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When your list is complete you should see the list displaying in the format chosen, for example a dropdown list as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/dropdownlist.png" alt="Dropdown list example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the list, click on the field itself and then click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin or Trash icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the field name and are sure this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-edit-list-properties">How to edit List properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To change the list properties, click on the field itself and the properties pane appears on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/listproperties.png" alt="List properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong>, List, is shown along with the **Title &lt;strong>of the field,&lt;/strong> in the example above Type of Training.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within properties are as follow, check the checkbox to implement:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show Title&lt;/strong> - show the title of the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - make this field mandatory for users to fill out&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - the field is enabled for users to fill out&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - the field is visible to users&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Max length&lt;/strong> - the maximum number of characters for the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - change the width of the field by clicking on the bar in the Layout box until you see the desired size. Click on the arrow beside Layout to see the Mobile Layout and click on the bar to change the width of the text box for mobile use.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxsize.png" alt="Changing text box width">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> - rules for input fields are covered in &lt;a href="rules/README.md">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Number control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/number/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Table control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/table/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Textbox control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/textbox/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Text box control&lt;/strong> is used to input text into a form for example a name or address. There are various options available when creating this field, these are explained below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to add a text box to a form - a sample video&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;video title="How to add a text box to a form" width="100%" style="width:100%" controls="controls">
&lt;source src="https://docs.kianda.com/videos/textbox.mp4" type="video/mp4">
&lt;/video>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add the Text box to your form click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Text box&lt;/strong>. The text box can also be placed within an element for example a panel, by clicking on the panel itself and then add the text box. Compare in the image below, the text box Name which is inside a panel versus Reason for the request which is outside the panel, both in the form Employee Request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxinout.png" alt="Text boxes inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To edit the Text box, click on the field itself and the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> appears allowing you to edit the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edittextbox.png" alt="Edit text box">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - of the field, for example Employee Name&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - information to help the form user&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) Single line of text b) Multiple lines of text c) Rich text&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose a) Single line of text then the following additional options are visible:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Control type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Text b) Password&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Autofill type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Default b) Off c) Password d) Address e) Email f) Phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Placeholder&lt;/strong> - placeholder text that can help the user to know what to fill out in the text box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose b) Multiple lines of text then the following additional options are visible:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Control type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Text b) Password&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Autofill type&lt;/strong> - options are a) Default b) Off c) Password d) Address e) Email f) Phone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Placeholder&lt;/strong> - placeholder text that can help the user to know what to fill out in the text box&lt;/p>
&lt;p>​ &lt;strong>Rows&lt;/strong> - the number of rows you would like for the text box&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text style&lt;/strong> - options are a) Normal b) Capitalise c) Uppercase d) Lowercase&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Max length&lt;/strong> - the maximum number of characters for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Text style&lt;/strong> - options are a) Normal b) Capitalise c) Uppercase d) Lowercase&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Expression&lt;/strong> - this can be used to return a value for example Date() returns the current date and time. For a full explanation of expressions go to &lt;a href="platform/expressions.md">Expressions&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxfilled.png" alt="Example of text box options">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="OK button"> when you are finished editing the field to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To move the text box, click on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="images/move.png" alt="Move button">on the text box field itself and drag it to where you want it to appear on the form, for example within a panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To change the text box properties, click on the field itself and the properties pane appears on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxproperties.png" alt="Text box properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="fields/properties.md">Properties&lt;/a> to find out more about options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To save your changes to the form, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the text box, click on the field itself and then click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin or Trash icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the field name and are sure this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Toggle control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/toggle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: User picker control</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/controls/input/user-picker/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>user picker field&lt;/strong> provides a way to associate a user to a particular task for example to allow a form user to find their manager to approve a workflow. This is achieved by connecting your Kianda form to a data source, for example information in SharePoint, and using the user picker field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To add a particular user, click on &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>User picker&lt;/strong>. The field can also be placed within an element for example a panel, by clicking on the panel itself and then add user picker field. Compare in the image below, the field Line Manager which is inside a panel versus Department Manager which is outside the panel, both in the form Employee Request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpickerinout.png" alt="User picker field inside and outside a panel">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Choose from the edit options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - of the user, for example Training Manager&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong> - this is a unique name for the field&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Help text&lt;/strong> - information to help the form user&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mode&lt;/strong> - options are a) Single or b) Multiple&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose b) Multiple then you can choose the maximum number of users to select by clicking on the arrow or simply typing your number into the box, for example 3 users as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/maxusers.png" alt="Maximum number of users to select">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Default to current user&lt;/strong> - options to default to the current user when in edit mode are a) No or b) Yes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Member of group&lt;/strong> - select the group from your data source that the user is a member of, for example HR Managers&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Selection options&lt;/strong> - choose from a) Users b) Groups c) Partners, as many as needed&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Default selection option&lt;/strong> - choose one from a) Users b) Groups c) Partners&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Show selection option menu&lt;/strong> - options are a) No or b) Yes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on the &lt;strong>OK&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ok.png" alt="Ok button"> when you are finished editing to save your changes or click on &lt;strong>Close&lt;/strong> to exit the dialog box without saving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you need to re-edit the user picker field, click on the field itself and the &lt;strong>Pen&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/penicon.png" alt="Pen icon"> appears allowing you to edit the field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpickeredit.png" alt="Editing the user picker field">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To move the field, click on the &lt;strong>Drag handle&lt;/strong> &lt;img src="images/move.png" alt="Move button">on the user picker field itself and drag it to where you want it to appear on the form, for example within a panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To save your changes to the form, click on the &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/saveprocess.png" alt="Save button">.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To delete the field, click on the field itself and then click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/binicon.png" alt="Bin or Trash icon"> and then click on &lt;strong>Ok&lt;/strong> after you have reviewed the field name and are sure this is what you want to delete. Click on &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong> if you wish to cancel the deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-edit-user-picker-properties">How to edit user picker properties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To change the user picker field properties, click on the field itself and the properties pane appears on the right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/userpickerproperties.png" alt="User picker field properties">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Field type&lt;/strong>, User picker, is shown along with the &lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> of the field, in the example above Training Manager.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The options within properties are as follows, check the checkbox to implement:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show Title&lt;/strong> - show the title of the field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Required&lt;/strong> - make this field mandatory for users to use&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Enabled&lt;/strong> - the field is enabled for users to use&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visible&lt;/strong> - the field is visible to users&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Layout&lt;/strong> - change the width of the field by clicking on the bar in the Layout box until you see the desired size. Click on the arrow beside Layout to see the Mobile Layout and click on the bar to change the width of the text box for mobile use.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/textboxsize.png" alt="Changing text box width">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> - rules for input fields are covered in &lt;a href="rules/README.md">Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>