<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Workflow rules</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/</link><description>Recent content in Workflow rules on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Assign form</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/assign-form/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/assign-form/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule is used to assign a form to a user or to a group of users. You can override the existing users or add to the existing users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Assign.png" alt="Assign rule dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To assign a form to a user:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select Controls &amp;gt; Input &amp;gt; User picker to add a field to store the user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on a button e.g. the Submit button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Add a rule &amp;gt; Workflow &amp;gt; Assign form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Action, select a form. You can select more forms by clicking the plus icon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For Assign to, select Defined in a user field. Then select the User picker field created earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set Existing user(s) to Override to make the selected user the only user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This rule can be used multiple times in sequence: typically the first rule overrides the existing users and the following rule(s) appends users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To view the default owners for the form, go to Edit form in the Designer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Go to form</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/go-to-form/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/go-to-form/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule is used to control how a user moves between forms. Normally control passes to the next form and the user is not allowed to go back to the previous form. The Go to form rule allows you to redirect the user to any form. The user can then navigate back and forth between those forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/Gotoform.png" alt="Go to form rule dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This rule may only be added to a button.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Close form and Go to form rules &lt;em>cannot&lt;/em> be applied to the same button as both rules control which form comes next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Save form rule must be used &lt;em>and&lt;/em> must appear before the Go to form rule in the list of rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To make the user go to a particular form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on a button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Add a rule &amp;gt;Workflow &amp;gt; Go to form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Action, choose the destination form from the list in the Select form field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Edit mode as the Display mode so that the user will be able to edit the destination form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose Yes (for Set as current form) to make the destination form the next active form. This will enable previously completed forms so that the user can navigate between these forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Display mode:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Auto - the display mode will be either edit or read as determined by the system. If the destination form is the next form in the process workflow, and if the user is an owner of the form, and the form is not completed, then the form will be displayed in edit mode. Otherwise the form will appear in read mode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edit mode - the user will be able to edit the destination form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Read mode - the user will be able to read (but not edit) the destination form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Set as current form:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Setting this flag to Yes will change the flow of control in your process. Check the current workflow in your process before making this change.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Process security</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/process-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/process-security/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule &lt;em>dynamically&lt;/em> changes the security settings of an instance of a process. You can set the security settings for a process by going to the Process Settings in the Designer. (If you tick Enable process security, you can then select users and their access level.) This setting is static and applies to every instance of the process. The Process security rule is &lt;em>dynamic&lt;/em> and changes the security settings for a particular instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ProcessSecurity.png" alt="Process security rule dialog box 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To change process security:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select Controls &amp;gt; Input &amp;gt; User picker to add a field to store the user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on a button e.g. the Submit button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Add a rule &amp;gt; Workflow &amp;gt; Process security&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Action, select Defined in a user field. Then select the User picker field created earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set Existing user(s) to Append to add the chosen user to the list of users of the process instance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set Override security settings to No. See below for more on this flag.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This rule can be used multiple times in sequence. You can use the first rule to override the existing users and the following rule(s) to append users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can override the process security settings by setting Override security settings to Yes. Tick Enable security to see the options for setting the security level. These options are identical to those in the Process Settings. See below.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Warning&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting Override security settings to Yes with Enable security &lt;em>not&lt;/em> ticked will disable all security settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ProcessSecurity2.png" alt="Process security rule dialog box 2">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Schedule a rule</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/schedule-a-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/schedule-a-rule/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule allows you to schedule a rule (or field e.g. a button with rules) to be triggered either immediately or at some point in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/ScheduleaRule1.png" alt="Schedule a Rule">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To schedule a daily reminder:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Select Controls &amp;gt; Actions &amp;gt; Button to add a button to the bottom of the form. Change the title of the button to Reminder. Go to the field property settings and make the button not visible to the user. You can add rules to this button that will be triggered daily e.g. send an email.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on another button e.g. the Submit button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Add a rule &amp;gt; Workflow &amp;gt; Schedule a Rule.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Action, select the new Reminder button as the field to be triggered.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Schedule, click on Daily.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set &lt;strong>At&lt;/strong> to 09:00 and &lt;strong>Every&lt;/strong> to 1. The Reminder button will be triggered at 9am every day.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>When the form is submitted, a new scheduled task is created. You can view all of the scheduled tasks in the system by selecting Administration &amp;gt; Scheduled Tasks and clicking on Show All in the top right hand corner of your screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h6>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Schedule&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="text-align:left">Options&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">One time&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Select &lt;strong>Time mode&lt;/strong> as Absolute or Relative from now. If &lt;em>Absolute&lt;/em>, you can select the time using the clock icon and the date using the calendar icon OR you can select a form field (where the date is stored) by clicking on the icon with black discs. If &lt;em>Relative from now&lt;/em>, enter the days, hours and minutes directly.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Minutes&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Every &amp;lt;select number of minutes&amp;gt; minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Hourly&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Minutes of hour &amp;lt;select number of minutes after the hour&amp;gt; Every &amp;lt;select number of hours&amp;gt;.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Daily&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">At &amp;lt;click on clock icon to select time&amp;gt; Every &amp;lt;select number of days&amp;gt;. Tick Week days to exclude Saturday and Sunday.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Weekly&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Weekday &amp;lt;select day&amp;gt; At &amp;lt;click on clock icon to select time&amp;gt; Every &amp;lt;select the number of weeks&amp;gt;.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Monthly&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Select &lt;strong>Day&lt;/strong>, &amp;lt;select the day&amp;gt; or &lt;strong>The&lt;/strong> &amp;lt;select which day e.g. First Monday&amp;gt;. At &amp;lt;click on clock icon to select time&amp;gt; Every &amp;lt;select number of months&amp;gt;.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">Immediately&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align:left">None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Note that all of the Schedule options are executed on the server side except the Immediately option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is possible to set the schedule rule to expire by ticking &lt;strong>Expire&lt;/strong>. There are three options:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>By: the rule will expire by the date and time given. Either select the time using the clock icon and the date using the calendar icon OR select a form field (where the date is stored) by clicking on the icon with black discs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After: the rule will expire after a set number of occurrences. Select the number of occurrences in the blank field or click on the icon with black discs to choose a field where the number of occurrences is stored.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When: add a condition which will cause the rule to expire when it is true.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Select &lt;strong>Make task unique&lt;/strong> if you want to prevent a second identical task being created for this instance of the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select &lt;strong>Execute in series&lt;/strong> if you want the server-side execution to be in series rather than in parallel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Show, hide or disable</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/hide-or-disable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/hide-or-disable/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule can perform one of the following actions on either fields or forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hide from the user (not visible)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show to the user (visible)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Disable for the user (not enabled)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable for the user (enabled)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toggle visible: toggle between visible and not visible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Toggle enable: toggle between enabled and not enabled&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hide and clear: hide from the user (not visible) and clear the contents&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/HideorDisable.png" alt="Hide or disable rule dialog box">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To dynamically &lt;em>hide&lt;/em> a field or component:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Choose a field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Add a rule &amp;gt; Workflow &amp;gt; Hide or disable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on Edit condition and add a condition.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Action, select a field or component to be made not visible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose Hide from the drop down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Add otherwise action, select the field or component to be made visible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose Show from the drop down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The result is that a field or component will be made visible/not visible depending on the condition that has been set.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is not necessary to add a condition. In this case the rule will be triggered automatically:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>if the rule is applied to a &lt;em>field&lt;/em>, then the rule will be triggered when the user enters a value in that field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if the rule is applied to a &lt;em>button&lt;/em>, then the rule will be triggered when the user clicks the button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if the rule is applied to a &lt;em>form&lt;/em>, then the rule will be triggered when the form is submitted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if the rule is applied to a &lt;em>process&lt;/em>, then the rule will be triggered on load.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If a rule causes a mandatory field (i.e. &lt;em>Required&lt;/em> is ticked in the Field Properties) to be hidden or disabled, this will not stop the form from being submitted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Start a process</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/start-a-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/rules/workflow/start-a-process/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This rule allows you to start a new instance of a different process (or a new instance of the same process). You can transfer field data from the current process instance to a new process instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/StartaProcess.png" alt="Process security rule dialog box 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when-to-use">When to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can add this rule:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> to a process (the rule will run on load)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-use">How to use&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To start an instance of a the Sample Process from the current process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click on a button e.g. the Submit button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select Add a rule &amp;gt;Workflow &amp;gt; Start a Process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Action, select Own process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Choose a target process design e.g. Sample Process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Input mapping, click on Add mapping. On the left side, choose a field from the current process. On the right side, select a destination field in the target process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click On success mapping. On the right side, type a message; on the left side, choose a field to store the message. Here data is being mapped back from the target process to the current process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The target process can be a &lt;strong>Partner process&lt;/strong>. The partner organisation must have enabled process security (in the Process settings for the target process) to allow your process to interact with the target process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use the &lt;strong>Lookup existing process&lt;/strong> flag to find a particular instance of the target process at runtime. If you select Yes, then you can select a field in the current process which contains the id of the target instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Table mapping&lt;/strong> allows you copy the contents of a table in the current process to a table in the target process. Click on Table mapping. On the right side, select a table in the current process; on the left side, choose a table in the target process. Click on the three dots icon to set the table mappings. If you select Copy rows and click on Copy row conditions you can control which rows are copied over to the target process. If you select Update rows and click on Update row conditions, then you can control which rows are updated with new data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use &lt;strong>Trigger rules in target instance&lt;/strong> to select a field or rule to trigger in the target process. Set Execute in series to Yes to ensure server side execution is performed in series instead of in parallel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another feature of this rule is that you can &lt;strong>read data from another process&lt;/strong> instance. In this case it is advisable to give the title of the rule a title such as Read data from Process X. Here you click On success mapping and use this area to copy data from the target process to the current process.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>