<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kianda no-code platform for business process automation – Administration</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/</link><description>Recent content in Administration on Kianda no-code platform for business process automation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: B2B Portals</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/b2b-portals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/b2b-portals/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Data sources</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/datasources/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong> function is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Manage datasources&lt;/strong>. Data sources is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The data sources function allows you to connect your processes to external data sources like SharePoint, Salesforce or SAP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connecting your data sources in this way allows real-time scalability, so as your organisation and data grows, the processes created in Kianda will continue to operate with these data sources, providing sustainable, flexible growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kianda comes with 19 predefined &lt;strong>data connectors&lt;/strong> allowing you to connect to these data sources. These are listed below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Active Directory&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DocuSign&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dropbox&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dynamics CRM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email&lt;/li>
&lt;li>File system&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FTP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GlobalPayments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google Drive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MySQL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Office 365&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oracle database&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PowerShell&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salesforce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SAP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SharePoint&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SOAP Service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SQL Server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>REST Service&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you are a developer and want to connect to a datasource that is not included in the predefined set, you can use SOAP or REST to create your own API for data transfer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To add a SharePoint data connector, the steps are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>To connect to a datasource, select &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> from the left-hand side pane and then click &lt;strong>Data sources&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>+ Add new&lt;/strong> button and then one of 19 data connectors, for example &lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the case SharePoint fill out the &lt;strong>Site URL&lt;/strong> and choose from options like &lt;strong>SharePoint version&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong> as in, if its a Site or Site Collection and &lt;strong>Authentication mode&lt;/strong>. For example, if you choose &lt;strong>System User Credentials&lt;/strong> as an authentication mode, you must provide your SharePoint system username and password.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on &lt;strong>Test connection&lt;/strong> and then &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once the data connector is created, this can be used with controls like lists and rules, for example in the image below, a SalesForce data connector called &amp;lsquo;Training&amp;rsquo; has been setup within the Data sources function. Lists within SharePoint can then be linked to list fields in Kianda, by clicking on Data connector in the Edit list dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/edit-list-eg.jpg" alt="Datasource">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about data connectors and how to use them, go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/connectors/">Connectors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Designer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/designer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/designer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>. Designer is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The Designer function allows you to create processes and forms using the intuitive easy-to-use no-code interface. Within Designer you can create forms, add controls and rules to create processes to work the way you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To start creating a process so that Kianda Designer will open:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You can view any created processes in the main process view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/process-view.jpg" alt="Process view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To view an existing process, click on a process name, or click on a folder or group to see processes within that group, for example a group like &lt;strong>Training&lt;/strong> in the image above.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new process, click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To import a process created for example in another workspace, click on &lt;strong>Import&lt;/strong>. Also note that from the main process view you can also export processes listed here for use in another workspace, by clicking on &lt;strong>Export&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a process using a predefined template, click on the &lt;strong>App Store&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new process, click on the &lt;strong>Add new&lt;/strong> button.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Add new process dialog box appears.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/new-process.jpg" alt="New process view">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this dialog box fill out the following fields:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong> - give the new process a title&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>ID&lt;/strong> - the Unique ID field is autofilled from the title field&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong> - a short description that describes the new process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Group&lt;/strong> - choose an existing group/folder to add the new process to, or type in a new group name to create a new group of processes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Administrators&lt;/strong> - choose from &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Groups&lt;/strong> or a mix of both users and groups for people who will be administrators of this process. The process administrator(s) is the only person/people who can edit &lt;strong>draft&lt;/strong> process designs. Once the process design is published, workspace administrators will be able to access the process design.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Once a process is opened, you are brought straight into Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/design-view.jpg" alt="Designer view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="designer-view">Designer view&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Designer&lt;/strong> is made up of three panes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In the left-hand pane, you will find the &lt;strong>Controls&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Rules&lt;/strong> as well as buttons to &lt;strong>Save&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Preview&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Publish&lt;/strong> processes, as well as exiting Kianda Designer to return to the main process view.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the centre pane, also called the &lt;strong>canvas&lt;/strong>, you can view form details and manipulate form fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the right-hand pane, you can view and edit process and field &lt;strong>properties&lt;/strong> as well as viewing rules assigned to fields, forms and processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about Designer and how to use the interface to create forms go to &lt;a href="https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/application-designer/">Application Designer&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Developer</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/developer/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Kianda &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong> is available to administrators and those users with the role &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>. The Developer function is found in the left-hand side pane, under &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong>. The function allows you to create customised field, rule and dashboard widgets using pre-defined widget UI and code templates that you can add your own code to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-get-started">How to get started&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To start using &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Administration&lt;/strong> in the left-hand side pane and then click on &lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any customised widgets that have been created will be visible in the main widget view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/developer-view.jpg" alt="Developer view">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>From the widget view you can click on the &lt;strong>Version History&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-version-history.jpg" alt="Version History button"> to view the widget creation history, or click on the &lt;strong>Edit&lt;/strong> (Pen) button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-edit.jpg" alt="Edit widget button">, or click on the &lt;strong>Bin/Trash&lt;/strong> button &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/widget-delete.jpg" alt="Delete widget button"> to delete a widget. To view widget details, click on the name of a widget.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To create a new widget click on &lt;strong>New widget&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next--idea-iconimages18png">What&amp;rsquo;s next &lt;img src="https://docs.kianda.com/images/18.png" alt="Idea icon">&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To read more about Developer and how to use the interface to low-code development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Recycle bin</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/recyclebin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/recyclebin/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Scheduled tasks</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/scheduledtasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/scheduledtasks/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Subscription</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/subscription/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Support</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/support/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Users &amp; Groups</title><link>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kianda.com/docs/platform/administration/users/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Page under construction&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>